本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
Doc, Help, Doc!
It Stopped Bleeding
That's Because Your Blood's
Freezing As It's Hitting The Air.
Here, Apply Pressureon It.
I Think My Legis Frozen.
That's The Leastof Your Problems.
The Blade Severedyour Femoral Artery.
Am I Gonna Lose My Leg?
Frostbite's Not Too Bad
But I Gotta Fix your Artery Now.
This Is Gonna Hurt.
You're Gonna Put That In Me?
Glue's The Best Wayto Repair
Your Artery At This Temperature.
It Looks Okay.
Here, Tear Offsome Pieces.
I Have To Check Your Foot.
Blood Flow Looks Good.
Your Leg Should Be Okay.
I Thought I Was Done.
Yeah, Like I'd Let Anything Happen To You.
You're The Only One
Who Can Fix The Generators.
One...Two...Three.
Cate, Cate, Are You Okay?
Are You Okay?
I--I--I Need Help.
Who Am I Supposed To Get?
本字幕仅供学习交流,严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
豪斯医生 第四季第11集
-=破烂熊字幕组=-
翻译:警察家属 手起星落y 玺爷 麦麦
校对:酒囊饭袋
时间轴:小苏 Kevinvan
Why Do I Even Give You An Office?
New Case.Psych Department
Asked For You Personally.
Patient's A Crazy Person?
You're A Crazy Person.
Patient's A Psychiatrist.
There's Something Wrong With Coma Guy's Cable.
He Seems Fine With It.
Your Patient Is An Adjunct
Faculty Member Here But Currently--
The Budget Committee Voted To
Charge For Cable In The Patient Rooms.
Slippery Slope.
Today We With Hold Porn,
Tomorrow It's Clean Bandages.
Talk To Carlson In Derm--
He Runs The Budget Committee--
After You Look At This.
After You Talk To Carlson,
-Maybe I'll--
-The Patient Is Trapped At The South Pole.
Any Possibility Of Evacuating Her?
That Wouldn't Be Any Fun.
And For The Next Two Months,
Winds Make It Impossible
To Fly Anything In Or Out.
Could Be Appendicitis Or A Gallstone.
Or A Kidney Stone.
That Wouldn't Be Any Fun.
If It's Appendicitis Down There,
Her Appendix Ruptures,She Dies,
There's Nothing We Can Do.
If It's Stones,She Takes Pain Meds,
The Stone Passes,
There's Nothing We Need To Do.
Could Be A Struvite Kidney Stone.
Most Kidney Stones Are Calcium And Benign.
Why Would You Suspect A Struvite Stone?
'Cause He Said Kidney Stones Were Boring.
It's Possible.
She's On Birth Control.
Lots Of Sex Could Lead
To Urinary Tract Infection,
Which Could Lead To An
Infection-Laced Struvite Kidney Stone.
Excessive Antarctic Drilling.
Bad For The Environment And The Ladies.
If It's A Struvite Stone
She Needs To Break It Up Quickly
Before The Infection Shuts Down Her Kidneys.
This Is Where It Gets Fun.
These Are The Supplies And
Medications She Has Available.
Nothing Here That Can Break Up A Kidney Stone.
What Else Do They Have Down There?
I Just Said--
I Don't Mean Medical Stuff.
Other Stuff.
Some Geological Equipment Breaks Ice
And Rock The Same Way We Break Kidney Stones.
Uh, Discovery Channel.
I Like Watching Them Blow Stuff Up.
Who Doesn't?
That Reminds Me.
Coma Guy Needs Cable.
Women's Billiard Is The Only
Thing That's Keeping Him Alive.
I'm Sure Carlson Will Be Moved By His Plight.
Carlson Won't Listen To
Me Since I Hit On His Wife.
You Knew!
God No, I Thought I Was Hitting On His Daughter.
Look, You're On The Committee.
He'll Listen To You.
I'm An Avid Reader Of "Committees
With Hotties" Message Boards.
I'm Not Oxicillin,500 Milligrams I.V.
Studies Conducted In Major Hospitals
Indicate That Happy Patients Recover Faster.
Studies Conducted In My Apartment
Show That Tv Makes People Happy.
Premium Channels Have A Particularly Striking Effect.
Charging Patients For Cable
Is Bringing In 13 Grand A Month.
Until This Injustice Is Righted,
I Am Going To Waste 13 Grand A Day.
It's $2.49 Down.
Get An Ekg And A Cardiac Enzyme.
If Those Check Out,Discharge Him
And Tell Him To Get A Snow Blower.
How Much Is 13 Grand Divided By $.04?
I Am Not Giving You Cable.
You're Gonna Have To Somehow Survive
With The Broadcast Networks Alone.
I'll Be Fine On Tuesdays.
If Sound Waves From The Flaw Detector Break The Egg,
It Should Safely Dissolve Your Kidney Stone.
This Isn't Going To Work.
There's No Reason It Shouldn't.
Sound Waves Are Sound Waves.
Stones Are Stones.
Some Are Bigger Than Others.
Some Are Inside Me.
How's It Going,Team Macgyver?
Oh, Great.
I Can't Get Cable,
But I Can Get The South Poleon Hi-Def.
We're Almost Readyto Start The Test.
Test?
Did Ford Test The Edsel?
Did Coke Test New Coke?
Did Shakespeare Test His Final Play: Snow Dogs?
I'm Guessing You're Doctor House?
I Was Wonderingwhen You Might Drop By.
Could She See Me?
Oh, Yeah.
Think Jagger Shows Up For The Sound Check?
Okay--Roadies,Off The Stage.
Go Help Cameron In The E.R.
Why?
No Way You're Just
Doing Her A Favor.
E.R. Is Standing Room Only.
Which Means Cameron's Bound
To Make A Mistake.
Find It
So I Can Blackmail Her.
As Far As You Know,
This Is Way More Than Just
Some Silly Battle
Over Cable.
Ready.
You-You Might Wanna
Just Dial It Down A Smidge.
I Am Not Doing This.
Your Kidney Stone Theory
Hinges On Me Having Sex, But-
Let Me Guess.
You're As Pure
As The Driven Snow.
Only If The Snow
Likes To Be On Top.
But I Am Here
Doing Psychological Research.
Generally Not A Good Idea
To Swap Fluids
With Your Subjects.
Struvite Stones Are Possible
In People Who Don't Have Sex.
They're Certainly Possible
In People Who Claim-
I've Had No U.T.I.S.
No Pain On Urination.
You Do Realize That Only One
Of Us Is A Real Doctor.
You Do Realize Only One Of Us
Has Any Control Over My Actions.
Dr. Milton, Are You Able
To Run A Chem 7?
Yes.
That'll Tell Us If Her Kidney
Function's Declining.
If It Is, He's Right.
Struvite Stone's
Most Likely Explanation.
If Not, She's Right.
Sorry, I Know How You Like
To Avoid
Avoiding Confrontation.
While We're Waiting
For That Test
To Prove Me Right,
Start I.V. Cefuroxime.
Keep The Infection In The Stone
From Wiping Out Your Kidneys.
I'll Send The Chem 7 Results
When I'm Done.
She's
A Great Psychiatrist.
One Session,
I've Got Shrinkage.
House Wants Us To Spy On You,
Report Back.
And You're Telling Me This
Because...
We Don't Want To Do It.
I Don't See A Problem
So Far.
If Our Choice Is
Between Pissing House Off
Or Pissing You Off,
That's Not Much Of A Choice.
So Unless I Give House Cable,
You're Gonna Make My Life
Miserable.
Yes.
And You're Telling Me This
So You Won't Feel As Guilty
When You Do It.
Yes.
Accommodating House's Every Whim
Is Not My Job Anymore.
But It Is Ours.
House Will Get
What He Wants.
Maybe We Should Just Pay
For It Ourselves
And Tell Him She Folded.
No.
Your Chem 7 Results
Show That Your Kidney Function
Is Declining.
Sounds Like A Kidney Stone
To Me.
The Decreased Function
Could Be From Dehydration
Caused By Vomiting
Due To A Gallstone.
You Agreed That The Chem 7
Would Decide
If It Was A Struvite Stone.
I Agreed To Do The Test.
The Results Are Up
For Interpretation.
I'll Redo The Test
In An Hour When I'm Rehydrated.
Have You Noticed
Any Improvement
Since Starting The Cefuroxime?
Not Really.
The Pain's About The Same.
While You're Waiting,
We Should Run Another Test
With The Geology Equipment.
You're Not Taking
The Cefuroxime.
She's Right Handed.
Means She Would've Put
The I.V. In Her Left Arm.
Catheter In The Arm
Makes It Hard
To Bend The Elbow The Way
People Do When They Drink!
We Have A Limited Supply
Of Medication
And I'm Not About To Waste It.
Last I Checked, You Had
A Limited Supply Of Doctors.
Right Before I Got Sick,
One Of My Crew Members
Severed His Femoral Artery.
He Needs The Cefuroxime.
Right, He Called Dibs.
His Need Is Definitive.
Mine Is Speculative.
You're Breathing Fast.
It's Because I'm Pissed Off!
Lift Up Your Chin.
Show Me Your Windpipe.
Ah!
My Chest Hurts.
It's Deviating To The Left.
Means Her Right Lung
Is Collapsing.
Cate, Is Anyone There With You?
Sean Went To The Mess.
You Need To Call Someone-
There's No Time.
Get A Syringe And A Needle.
Why Am I Doing-
Shut Up And Look.
She Could Pass Out.
She Needs-
She Needs To Reinflate
That Lung
Okay, Now Pull Out
The Plunger.
I Want You To Stab Yourself
In Your Right Side
Between The Second
And Third Rib
In The Mid-Clavicular Line.
By The Time We Get
Someone Else There,
You'll Have Suffocated.
Just Do It.
See All The Good Stuff
That Happens
When You Listen To Me?
Means It's Not
A Kidney Stone.
Right Side Pain,
Vomiting,
And Now A Lung
That Gets Traumatized
Without Any Trauma.
Sounds Odd.
Probably Is Odd.
We Should Discuss This,
Then Call Her Back.
Oh, That's Fine.
I Made Sure We Got
The South Pole
Long Distance Plan.
Your Latest Kidney Function
Test Shows-
I Know What It Shows.
I Ran It.
The More You Interrupt,
The Longer My Grandstanding
Is Gonna Take.
Since When Do You Let Patients
Participate In Differentials?
Since The Patient
And Her Doctor
Happen To Be The Same Person.
Your Kidney Function
Is Still Declining.
Means You Have
A Kidney Problem.
But Not One That Needed
Antibiotics.
Makes Us Equally Wrong.
No, Makes Us Both Wrong.
Not Equally.
You Were At Least Six Wronger.
They Run A Ppd
Before You Shipped Out?
On Me And Everybody Else Here.
It's Not T.B.
Excuse Us A Second.
Cancer Explains The Symptoms.
A Tumor In Her Lung
Or Kidney
That Threw A Clot
To The Other Organ.
And You're Worried
The Tumor Might Overhear,
Realize We're On To It.
Cancer's A Hard Diagnosis
For Patients
Even When They're Not
In The South Pole.
We Should Figure This Out,
Maybe Bring Wilson In.
Obviously You Two
Think I'm In Bad Shape.
Only If You Count The Tumor.
House!
Probably In Your Abdomen.
But You Don't Have
Any Advanced
Imaging Equipment.
You Also Don't Have
A Surgeon To Biopsy It,
Any Stains To Use
On The Slide,
Or An Oncologist
To Analyze It.
Too Far Away
To Hold Her Hand.
I Have Cancer?
Possibly.
Since The Only
Imaging Equipment
You Have Is X-Ray,
Let's Start There.
X- Ray Your Entire Body.
I'll Upload The Images
When I'm Done.
Good For You.
She's Annoying.
Refused To Take The Antibiotics
Because Other People
Might Need Them.
She Said She Cares
About Other People?
What A Poser.
K.U.B. Is Clean.
You Don't Like Her
Because She's A Psychiatrist.
I'm A Complicated Man.
I Loathe Her For Many Reasons.
Never Before Has A Profession
Been So Decried
By Someone Who Needed It
So Badly.
You Talk A Lot Of Smack
About Tranny Hookers.
Enlarged Mediastinal Node.
Lymphoma.
Probably,
But We Can't Confirm It
Without A Biopsy.
You Can't Analyze A Biopsy
Without A Stain.
We Can't Biopsy.
'Cause They Don't Have Stains
Down There.
We Need A Substitute.
She Can't Biopsy That Node
Without A Surgical Team
And An O.R.
Anything With A Strong Color
Could Work As A Stain.
Printer Ink, Food Coloring,
Coffee.
No Thanks.
??? One She Can Biopsy.
That Makes Sense.
That Makes Sense?
I Said It First.
In A Shockingly Calm Manner
After I'd Just Been Jerking You
Around For 30 Seconds
Without You Complaining
Or Analyzing Said Jerking.
I Was Being Mature.
In A Lavender Shirt.
You For Some Reason Are Happy.
How Dare You?
The X-Rays Don't Show
Any Other Abnormal Nodes.
Abnormal Nodes
Can Be Felt
Before They Can Be Seen
On An X-Ray.
You're Wearing That Shirt
For Someone.
The Health Department.
They Frown
On Topless Oncology.
You're Gonna Do A Physical?
Have To.
You And Foreman
Are Gonna Be Here
Looking For A Stain.
I Can Do The Physical.
There's No Reason To Watch.
I Can Think Of At Least
Three Reasons.
One Of Them's Medical.
Where Are You?
Not In Your Office.
You're Not In The Hospital.
No Reason For Me To Be.
I Am Not Undressing For You
In Your Apartment.
You're Not In My Apartment.
You're Three Quarters
Of A World Away.
I Promise Not To Get Fresh.
I'm Not Taking Off
My Clothes.
One Of Us Has To.
Show Me Your Place.
Uh, It's Got Walls,
A Floor,
And In Some Places, A Roof.
I Am Not Exposing Myself
Without Some Reciprocity.
It's My Apartment.
It's Not My Soul.
Living Room.
Slow Down.
Huh, Lots Of Books.
I'm Betting All Medical.
Only If You Count
Jenna Jameson's Autobiography
As A Gynecological Text.
Fiction Is A Waste Of Time
Unless You Can Laugh At It.
I Love To Laugh.
Moving On.
Back Up.
How Bad Is The Insomnia?
Let Me Clarify That.
Do You Drink Two
Or Three Scotches
Before Passing Out
In Front Of The Tv?
You Are So Far Off.
It's Bourbon.
No Photos Anywhere.
Family And Friends
Aren't Important?
Well, You're Sick.
You Got 20 People
Down The Hall
And You've Had
Exactly One Visitor.
I Don't Want To Panic Anyone.
You Don't Like People.
You Hide On That Ice Cube
So People-
Stop Projecting.
You're Anti-Social,
So You Assume I'm Anti-Social.
How About If I Just Get Naked
And You Shut Up?
If I Thought I Could
Get You Naked,
I Would've Led With That.
You'd Rather Show Me
Your Soul Than Your Leg.
Great, You Got Me
All Figured Out.
You Gonna Try And Fix Me Now?
I Never Said
You Needed Fixing.
He's Letting Her Take Part
In The Differentials.
Of Course He Is.
He Likes Her.
Big Shock, Spaghetti Sauce
Doesn't Work
As A Lymph Tissue Stain.
I'll Try The Coffee.
He's Annoyed By Her,
Doesn't Respect Her
As A Doctor,
Constantly Insults Her.
That's House's Version
Of Courtship.
Oh, God.
He's Been Wooing Me
For Years.
She's The Perfect Woman
For Him.
Willing To Literally Go
To The End Of The Earth
For Her Career,
Making Her Unavailable
For A Real Relationship.
And She's Afflicted
With A Mysterious Illness.
Soy Sauce Is A No-Go.
We're Gonna Be Here
All Night.
How Long Does It Take You
To Get Naked?
It's The South Pole.
I Wear A Lot Of Layers.
Okay, Ready.
Bah!
I Saw Socks.
That's Not Naked.
Have I Mentioned
It's Freezing Here?
When They Discover Lymph Nodes
In Feet,
I Will Take Off My Socks.
Use Your Right Hand
To Palpate The Nodes.
Any Node You Can Feel
Is One You Can Biopsy.
Let's Start With Your Breasts,
Move Down To The Ass,
Then-
I Was Thinking
Go From The Neck
And Work My Way Down.
Well You Could,
But I'd Never Forgive Myself
If We Found Something Before
We Got To Your Breasts.
I'm Starting With
The Anterior Cervical Nodes.
Turn Your Head.
Locate The Scm Muscle.
I Know How To Find
My Lymph Nodes.
They Teach You That Before
Or After The Class
On Fondling Your Inner Child?
No Swelling,
No Tenderness,
And I Can Hear That, House.
Just Thought
It Might Help You Relax.
Anything In The Axillary Nodes?
All Clear.
Both Sides.
Slide Your Hand
To Your Sternum,
Probe For Nodes.
Moving Slowly Downward.
Down To What, House?
Sorry, Can't Hear You
On Account
Of Your Heavy Breathing.
I'm Supposed To Be
On Oxygen, You Tool.
Hold It.
Your Fingers Didn't Go
Quite As Deep.
Feel That Node Again.
It-It's Swollen.
Looks Like You're Doing
A Biopsy.
It's Pretty Numb.
Okay, Take A Deep Breath
And Insert The Needle
Into The Node.
Come On, Cate.
Let's Get This Over With.
You Used Her Name.
Just Trying To Move Things
Along, Bob.
Okay, I'm In.
You Need To Pull Back
On The Syringe.
You Need To Pull Harder.
You Okay?
Yeah.
"Are You Okay?"
It's A Valid Medical Question.
I Have Never Heard You
Ask A Patient That Question.
You've Never Asked Me
That Question,
And You've Seen Me Fall Down
A Flight Of Stairs Drunk.
You've Slept With Her.
She's 9,000 Miles Away.
And While A Certain Part Of Me
Unfurled-
No, You-
Somehow You've Been Intimate
With Her.
Why Are You Following Me?
Thought You Were Following Me.
No, You Are Definitely
Following Me.
Where Are You Going?
Out To Lunch.
You Never Go Out
To Lunch.
Means There's A Reason
You're Going Out To Lunch.
I Assume That Reason
Is A Human Being.
Or A Sandwich.
Sandwiches Can Come Here.
So Can Human Beings.
Yet She's Not,
Which I Find Interesting.
I'm Leaving Now.
Small World.
Are You Going To Follow Me
Into My Car?
It's Got Two Doors.
Okay, Look-
The Reason I Haven't Told You
Is-
Call Off Your Dogs,
House.
Your Little Helpers
Are Interrogating My Patients,
Swiping My Charts,
Intercepting Prescriptions.
Why Would You Think
That I'm-
Because I'm Not A Moron.
You Had To Be Pulling
The Strings Here.
You Think That Because
They Make Me Miserable
I'm Gonna Give You Cable?
Let's Assume
That's True.
And It Certainly Sounds
Like It Might Be.
What Are You Gonna Do?
Nothing.
I Resigned
From The Budget Committee.
I Only Joined The Committee
To Help The Hospital.
You Made Me A Liability.
I Now Have Zero Influence
Over The Hospital's
Cable Policy.
Well Done.
It Didn't Work.
There's Nothing More That-
Put These Up.
"Free Rottweiler Puppies.
Please Call After 11:00 Pm
And Before 5:00 Am."
Is This Cameron's
Home Number?
I Love A New Puppy.
That Last One
Was Delicious.
In Torturing Her.S No Point
If She Can Resign,
She Can Unresign.
Go To Defcon One.
Forget Waiting For A Mistake,
Make Her Make One.
You Want Us To Sabotage
Another Doctor,
Possibly Harm A Patient,
All So You Can Have Cable.
Harm Suggests Permanent Damage.
Get Her To Screw Up,
Then Fix It.
Oh, And This Time
Don't Tell Her
What You're Gonna Do
Before You Do It.
So, Um, How Long
Do I Let The Lymph Node
Marinate In The Red Wine?
It Should Be Ready Now.
Try Increasing The Magnification
On The Camera.
You Know, I E-Mailed
A Couple Colleagues
At The Hospital About You.
You're Checking Up On Me,
Not House?
Yeah, Well House
Is Straightforward,
Brilliant, And An Ass.
Two Out Of Three Good Qualities,
Clear Majority.
Whereas You,
On The Other Hand,
Have A Perfect Score.
You Are Responsible,
Nice, Human.
And Yet You're House's
Best Friend.
Hold There.
Makes You Think He's Secretly
Nicer Than He Seems?
Makes Me Think That
You're Secretly
A Lot Less Nice
Than You Seem.
Do You Always Insult
Your Doctors?
It's Not An Insult.
Indiscriminate Niceness
Is Overrated.
No Wonder He Likes You.
Based On This Slide,
You Do Not Have Cancer.
Oh.
Thank God.
I Do See Some Inflammation
Which Could Mean-
Ah-Mm-
Cate?
You All Right?
My Left Side... Hurts.
Um...
It's The Same Pain
That I Had On The Right.
Your Other Kidney.
No, I Hope It's Something, Um-
It's Maybe-
Ah!
Oh, No!
I'm Screwed.
Bad News Is You're 0 For 2
In The Kidney Department.
Is There Good News?
You're Back At Home.
Of Course.
There's Cable.
And The Freedom To Work
Pant-Free.
That Is Good News.
Wilson Found Signs
Of Inflammation In Your Biopsy.
That Plus
The Two Failing Kidneys
Points To Autoimmune Disease.
Probably Sle Or Vasculitis.
Treatment For Both
Is Prednisone.
Start With 100 Milligrams-
Autoimmune Is Just
Your Latest Theory.
Like Cancer Before That,
And A Kidney Stone Before.
Take The Prednisone,
You'll Get Better,
That'll Be Your Confirmation.
You Practice Medicine
Like It's A Fire Sale.
You've Wasted Antibiotics,
X- Rays-
That Was Not A Waste.
We Ruled Out-
We Have A Crew Member Here
Who Has Asthma.
If He Has An Episode
After I've Used Up
The Prednisone, He'll Die.
There's A Good Chance
He's Gonna Die Anyway,
Since There Won't Be
A Doctor There To Help Him.
Show Me Proof
That It's Autoimmune
And Then I'll Take
The Prednisone.
We Should Send Her Outside.
Right, Just Tell Her
To Head North
Until She Runs Into
A Hospital.
Autoimmune Diseases
Are Basically
Inflammation Running Wild.
Extreme Cold Has Been Used
As Treatment,
Like Putting Ice
On A Sprained Ankle.
She Starts To Feel Better
Outside,
We Know It's Autoimmune.
Is That My Wallet?
Yeah, You Can Have It Back.
I've Already Been Through It.
I Like Your
"Ice On A Sprain" Metaphor.
Makes It Seem Like
We're Not Killing Her.
She'd Only Need To Be Outside
Five Minutes.
Without Her Mittens.
Mom Told Me That
Was A Bad Idea.
Especially That Winter
It Was 70 Below
And I Had Dual Kidney Failure.
This Is A Good Idea.
It's Perfect For You-
Experimental, Risky.
Wilson's Right.
You Care About-
You Didn't Touch The Cash,
But You Took
The Receipts?
$190 Restaurant Tab.
That's Dessert,
Probably Booze.
Means You Lingered.
Means It's At Least
The Third Date.
Means-
Where Are You Going?
To Talk To The People I Pay
To Come Up With Medical Ideas.
There Are No Ideas.
The Test For Autoimmune
Is A.N.A.
Unless Penguins Poop
Immuno Analyzers, She's Not-
Before A.N.A. Testing,
People Had Autoimmune Diseases.
How Did They Know?
C3.
Before That.
L.E. Prep.
But She Doesn't Have
Any Controlled Pore
Glass Beads.
You Don't Need Them.
When You Shake
The Test Tube,
The Paperclip Will Damage
Some Of Your Blood Cells.
If You Have An Autoimmune
Disease,
Your Immune System
Will Gorge Itself
On The Damaged Cells.
They'll Get Big And Fat
So You Can See 'Em
Under A Microscope.
How You Doing?
No Change.
So How Long Should
I Give The Cells
To Fatten Up Before
I Check Them?
Couple Hours.
Or You Could Stop
Being A Hypocrite
And Take The Prednisone Now.
Not Bending To Your Will
Makes Me A Hypocrite?
If Your Psych Patients
Demanded Lab Results,
You'd Never Make A Diagnosis.
So I'm Wrong.
You Sleep Like A Baby,
Your Life Is Unfolding
As You Dreamed.
Everyone Is Miserable.
You Don't Change That
Because People Don't Change.
You Want To Believe That
Because Then You're Freed
From Any Responsibility
For Your Misery.
Oh, Shut Up.
I Get Enough Of This
From Wilson.
And Yet You Keep Hanging Out
With Him.
And From What I Hear,
You Have Spent More Time
With Me
Than With Any Other Patient.
Sorry About That.
Call Me When You Get
The Results.
How's Your Patient?
She Has
An Autoimmune Disease.
Tell The Psych Department
She's In Denial.
I Had To Fire Cameron.
What?
What Happened?
65-Year-Old Man
Came Into The E.R.
With A Hip Fracture.
Cameron Gave Him Demerol.
The Guy Was
On An M.A.O.I.
Put Him
Into A Hypertensive Crisis.
Is He Gonna Live?
Taub Caught The Error
In Time.
If She'd Just Admitted
The Mistake,
Maybe I Could've Just
Suspended Her.
But She's Packing Up,
If You Want To Say Good-Bye.
We Should Be Hearing
From The South Pole
In A Few Minutes.
That's It?
There's Nothing To Be Done.
She Screwed Up.
She's Got No One To Blame
But Herself.
I Gotta Go Talk
To Cameron.
Cuddy Wouldn't Can Her
For One Screw-Up.
And If She Did,
She Wouldn't Come To Me.
She Wouldn't Open With,
"How's Your Patient."
And If She Did-
Why Would She Lie?
Timeless Question.
In This Case, She Conspired
With Your Coworkers
To Teach Me
That Some Things
Are More Important
Than Cable.
And I'm Gonna Have To Teach Them
That They're Wrong.
Come On, South Pole
Really Should Be Calling.
L.E. Prep Test Was Negative.
It's Not Autoimmune.
You're Basing That On A Test
Done With A Paperclip.
Just Take The Prednisone.
Either Find Another Diagnosis
Or Find Another Test.
There Is One Way.
You Can Take This Experimental
Drug Called...
Prednisone!
Your Kidneys Start Working-
There Is Another Test.
Oh, I-I Think Foreman
May've Just Broken Up There.
What He Actually Said Was
"There Is No Other Test."
If You Have
An Autoimmune Disease,
Exposure To The Cold
Should Decrease
Your Kidney Pain.
If I Go Outside,
We'll Have Our Answer?
And You Knew About This?
I Rejected It Because
If You're Frozen Solid,
It's Hard To Get The Needles
Into Your Arms.
How Long Do I Need
To Stay Out?
At Least Five Minutes.
Eight Minutes Outside
Would Kill A Healthy Person.
And Healthy People Don't
Suck On Oxygen Masks.
Healthy People
Can Pee.
I'll Go Get Sean,
Have Him Come With Me.
Just Take The Prednisone.
Once I Come Inside.
If It's Autoimmune.
Are You All Right?
Oh, I'm Sure
She's Just Fine.
Cate?
See If There's Anye
Down There
Who Has A Cell Phone.
Took The Station Mechanic
20 Minutes To Respond.
She'd Already Slipped
Into A Coma.
Started Her On Prednisone,
But No Improvement.
Means It's Not Autoimmune.
Good Thing She's In A Coma,
Or We'd Have To Listen
To Her Gloat.
And Where Are We Going?
To Find The Useful Members
Of My Team.
You're Letting Him
Off The Hook?
Happy?
Because Of You,
I'm Not Gonna Be Able
To Watch Law And Order
In Korean
Why Am I Here?
Because I Want To Ask You
About Your Girlfriend.
I Must Know Who She Is
Or You'd Have Told Me
Her Name.
She Doesn't Have A Name.
It's Some Sort
Of Birth Defect.
There's Only About
12 People We Both Know.
I Can't Remember
Five Of Their Names,
So We're Down To...
Cuddy..Your Ex-Wife
Your Mama.
You Need To Run
A Kidney Function Test.
Yes, If Only
She Wasn't In A Coma
We Could Get Her To Run
A Test To Find Out
Why She's In A Coma.
The Results Would Likely
Be Paradoxical.
Can't Be Cuddy,
'Cause You're Straight.
Can't Be-
We Could Talk The Mechanic
Through The Test.
Too Complicated.
Unless He's Thirsty.
Drink Her Urine?
If It Has A Strong,
Concentrated Taste,
It Means The Problem's
In Her Kidneys.
Watery Taste Means
It's Her Brain
And Then You Can Fix It?
Let's Say Yeah.
How Do I Get The Urine
Out Of Her?
Take A Straight Catheter
And Insert It-
These Are Your Only Questions?
Not, "Is It Safe?"
Or, "Is There Another Way?"
Or, "Are You Out
Of Your Minds?"
You Wouldn't Ask Me If-
Wait A Second.
You're In Love With Her.
That Explains Why
You're So Eager
To Get Her Naked,
Then Have A Drink.
'Cause Most Guys Like
To Go The Other Way Around.
Why Do You Care
How I Feel About Her?
Because Now I Know
That I Can Get You
To Do Anything To Save Her.
Tell Him How
To Tap The Keg.
You Got Cameron Fired.
Uh, Cuddy Wasn't Supposed
To Find Out.
No Kidding!
Get Me Cable.
How Tough Can That Be?
Cost A Woman
Her Job.
There's Only One Thing
You Can Say
To Keep Me From Firing You.
Cameron Wasn't Fired.
Wrong.
You Know?
We'r Still Fired?
That Should Be A Hint
As To What You're Supposed
To Say.
We're Sorry.
Wrong.
I Love You.
This Is A Game?
First We Have To Screw
With Our Coworker
And Now We Have To Try
To Figure Out
What You Want Us To Say?
This Is Insane.
I'm Not Playing.
Right.
Should've Said This
Two Days Ago.
Do Not Play Games
With Me.
Number One,
You're Going To Lose.
You're Just Not Ready.
Number Two, The Game
Was To Force You
To Stop Playing Games.
I Need You To Stand Up
To Me.
Challenge Me.
I Need You To Stop Worrying
About Getting Fired.
Go Pay For My Cable.
No!
I Didn't Mean On This.
Seriously, I Need Cable.
Milk, Milk, Lemonade.
Uh, This Tastes Kind Of Watery.
That's Bad News.
Either Increased
Intracranial Pressure
Or Something's Wrong
With Her Hypothalamus.
How Do You Figure Out
Which One It Is?
We Don't Do Anything.
You're Gonna Drill
A Hole In Her Skull.
If She Regains Consciousness,
It's Increased
Intracranial Pressure.
And If It's The Other Thing?
She'll Die.
But If It's The Hypothalamus,
She's Dead Anyway.
If The Problem Is The Pressure
In Her Brain,
And I Fix It,
Is She Gonna Be All Better?
Nope, But It'll Give Us
More Time
To Figure Out What's Wrong.
I Have To Get Someone Else.
I Can't Do This.
You Love Her, Right?
You'd Do Anything
To Save Her.
Not This.
I Can't Do This.
If-If She Dies Because
Of Something
That I Did, Then I-
Listen, Listen.
I Am Not Going
To Let You Hurt Her.
Okay?
Now Please...
This Is Her Only Chance.
Okay.
Well, That Was Easy.
Okay, Her Head Is Stabilized
And The Drill Bit
Is Sterile.
Place The Drill Bit Against
The Upper Left Part
Of Her Forehead.
About An Inch Above
The Temple.
It's Not Going Anywhere.
Bone's Harder Than Wood.
Lean Into It.
The Skull's Only
A Quarter-Inch Thick.
Once You're Midway Through,
Drill In Shorter Bursts.
If It Comes Out
The Other Side,
You've Gone Too Far.
Okay, Now What?
Now What?
Let The Fluid Drain.
She's Waking Up.
Sean?
What's Going On?
South Pole Doc
Is Out Of Her Coma,
And Now We Have
A New Symptom:
Increased Intracranial
Pressure.
Why Are We Out Here?
That's The Patient Room.
Icp Plus Kidney Problems
Plus Lung Collapse Equals?
The Most Likely Suspect
Is A Tumor
Throwing Off Clots.
We Ruled Out Cancer.
But Not Clots.
What Causes Blood Clots?
Bacterial Endocarditis.
Not Without A Fever.
Deep Vein Thrombosis Plus
An Existing Pfo.
Pfo Would've Been Discovered
In Her Pre-South Pole
Physical Exam.
What If The Clots
Aren't Clots?
Atherosclerosis.
Fatty Plaque Builds Up
On The Arterial Walls,
Pieces Break Off,
Block Blood Flow.
Explains Everything.
She Has Zero Risk Factors.
Forget Fat, Think Clots.
No.
You're Standing Up To Me?
Maybe.
Just To Clarify.
You Should Do That
When You're Right.
Sorry For The Confusion.
How Could A Clot-
Could Be A Different Kind
Of Fat, Fat Emboli.
That's A Perfect Fit...
Except It's Completely
Impossible!
Fat Emboli Requires
An Unrepaired Bone Break.
Between The X-Ray
And The Exam,
I've Seen Her Entire-
See, That's What
I'm Talking About.
Take Off Her Socks.
I Could-I Could Do It.
No, I Got It.
Your Toe Is Broken.
Oh, My God.
Bits Of Bone Marrow
Have Been Leaking
Into Your Blood Stream.
Those Fat Emboli
Have Caused Blockages
In Your Kidney, Lungs,
And Brain.
It Doesn't Even Hurt.
Cold Numbs Everything.
Does A Particularly Great Job
On The Extremities.
You'll Need To Close
The Break
So Stop The Marrow
From Leaking.
This One You Will Feel.
Will You Do It?
He Drilled A Hole
In Your Skull
After Drinking Your Pee.
I Think He's Up For This.
Grab The Tip Of Her Toe
With Your Right Hand.
Hold The Break With Your Other.
On The Count Of Three,
Pull Hard.
One... Two...
Three.
Now Splint Your Toe.
You'll Be Fine.
Thank You, House.
Don't Thank Me.
He's The One
Who Saved Your Life.
He Likes Her.
A Bottle Of The Bordeaux
And Some Sparkling Water.
Well, You
Didn't Pick Her Up.
Which Means She's Coming
From Work Too.
Which Means You're
Comfortable Enough To Meet Her.
Damn.
Thought I Lost You
When I Walked Backwards
Through My Own Footprints
In The Snow.
I Think I've Got It
Narrowed Down
To Three Possibilities.
Better Leave.
If You See Her,
It'll Be Cheating.
It's Not One
Of Your Ex-Wives.
Because They Hate Me.
They Don't.
They Should, But They Don't.
I Called Them.
Someone New,
But Someone I Know.
Did You Ever Consider
Being Happy For Me?
Briefly.
You Ordering The Wine
Before She Got Here.
Girls Are Good, House.
And You Know It.
You Solved Your Case
Because You Cared
About That Girl.
You're Demonstrating
The Illusion
Of Manly Confidence.
Which Means You Haven't Closed
The Deal Yet.
I Closed The Deal.
I Just Like Her.
Still?
You Knew Your Patient
Hated Having Cold Feet
Because You Did
A Physical Exam,
Because You Liked Her-
Your Theory Is I Cared,
Therefore I Let Her Keep
Her Socks On?
If That's What Love Is,
Then I Don't Want To Have
Anything To Do With It.
It Starts With Warm Feet,???
Your Mom And I Will Explain
When You're Older.
If I'd Made Her Take Them Off
Like I Should've,
I Would've Seen The Toe
And I Would've Solved The Case
Days Ago.
But You Don't Care
About Her.
Of Course Not.
House Doesn't Care
About Anyone.
Hi.
Sorry I'm Late.
Cut Throat Bitch?
I Call Her Amber.
Was She On Your List?
破烂熊字幕组
-==Http://Www.Ragbear.Com==-
欢迎加入
www.tvsubtitles.net