OH. HOW THE...
(House)
## WELL, I GUESS
IT WOULD BE NICE ##
## IF I COULD TOUCH
YOUR BODY ##
## I KNOW NOT EVERYBODY ##
## HAS GOT A BODY LIKE YOU ##
## BABY ##
YOU KNOW,
MOST PEOPLE GO FOR THE HARDWOOD
OR CARPETING.
I THINK GUITARS AND GARBAGE
WORK JUST AS WELL.
GOT THE URGE TO PLAY
LAST NIGHT.
HAD TO GO ALL THE WAY BACK
TO MY APARTMENT.
THOUGHT I'D SAVE
ON FUTURE TRIPS.
HMM. IT'S VERY ECO-FRIENDLY
OF YOU.
HOW ABOUT KEEPING DOWN
ON THE NOISE POLLUTION?
6:33. YOU SHOULD BE FLOSSING
BY NOW.
I'M NOT GOING TO WORK TODAY.
I'M GOING HUNTING.
AFTER I SLEEP IN.
AH. AH.
OH.
IS IT THAT TIME
OF YEAR AGAIN?
HE'S A SELF-IMPORTANT JERK.
HE'S MY FRIEND.
SEEMS TO BE
WHAT I'M ATTRACTED TO.
GUY CALLS YOU JIM.
DOESN'T EVEN KNOW YOUR NAME.
JIM IS SHORT FOR JAMES.
NOW GO AWAY, LIM.
[gunshot]
NICE SHOT, JIM.
OH, YEAH.
I NAILED THAT TREE.
[loads bullet]
MAPLE SYRUP FOR DINNER.
WE SHOULD HAVE GOT
A GUIDE.
OH, DOESN'T COUNT
AS NEW ADVENTURE
IF YOU HAVE SOMEONE HOLDING
YOUR HAND.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
WE ARE HOLDING WEAPONS
AND HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT WE'RE DOING.
FUN.
WELL, WE NEED
TO SNEAK UP ON THEM.
I READ SOMEWHERE THAT
THE NATIVE AMERICANS SAY
TURKEYS KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
SO I SHOULD STOP THINKING
ABOUT GERMAN PORN.
NO, NO.
THAT'LL LURE THEM CLOSER.
[turkeys calling
and gobbling]
[turkeys gobble and scatter]
WE'RE TERRIBLE AT THIS.
YEAH. WELL, AT LEAST IT'S COLD
AND MY NEW BOOTS LEAK.
WELL, IT'S ALMOST TIME
ANYWAY.
DID YOU BRING THE BAG?
MAY 30, 2004.
10:07 A.M.
DR. WILSON INFORMED ME
THAT IF TREATMENT
DIDN'T GO WELL,
MY LEUKEMIA WOULD GIVE ME
ONLY SIX MORE MONTHS TO LIVE.
NOVEMBER 30, 2004.
SIX MONTHS LATER,
I DIDN'T DIE.
AS LONG AS I AM ALIVE,
I WILL FIND NEW AND EXCITING
WAYS TO THANK YOU
FOR GIVING ME ANOTHER YEAR.
NOW MOVE VERY, VERY FAR
AWAY FROM THERE
SO THAT I CAN BE SURE
AND THANK YOU AGAIN
NEXT YEAR.
[clears throat]
[loads bullet]
THANKS, JIM.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S SEE HOW MANY
MORE TURKEYS WE CAN MISS.
[turkey call
groans impotently]
YEAH, THIS WILL WORK.
[gunshot]
WHAT THE HELL?
GOD.
SORRY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
I CAN'T MOVE MY ARM.
AM I HAVING A STROKE?
I DON'T KNOW.
[exhales]
[Massive Attack'sTeardrop]
## ##
GOOD NEWS.
HEAD CT DOESN'T SHOW
ANY SIGNS OF A STROKE.
SO HE'S GONNA BE OKAY,
RIGHT?
I CANNOT BELIEVE
HOW MUCH YOU'VE GROWN UP
IN FIVE YEARS.
SHE'S...
SHE'S NOT FAMILY.
ASHLEY, MY GIRLFRIEND.
NEW LIFE, NEW ADVENTURES.
ASHLEY, MEET JIM.
IT'S GOOD TO MEET YOU.
SO THIS ARM THING,
DOES THAT MEAN
HIS LEUKEMIA'S BACK?
I CHECKED BLOOD COUNTS
AND BLOOD CELL MORPHOLOGIES.
EVERYTHING IS NORMAL.
SO THESE BLOOD TESTS,
IT MEANS IT'S NOT CANCER
FOR SURE.
HE SAID I'M FINE.
SO WHAT DO YOU THINK IT IS?
HOPEFULLY SOMETHING
INNOCUOUS.
THERE'S A DOCTOR I CAN SPEAK TO
WHO'S GREAT...
WHO'S GREAT
AT DIAGNOSING...
WHAT?
SORRY, THAT COLD SORE,
HOW LONG
HAVE YOU HAD THAT?
UM, TWO WEEKS.
I'M SORRY.
I-I GOT THE CALL.
I DIDN'T HAVE TIME
TO COVER IT UP.
WHAT IS IT, JIM?
[laughs]
THAT COLD SORE IS CAUSED
BY A VIRUS.
ASSUMING YOU GUYS KISS,
THE VIRUS COULD TRANSFER,
INFECT YOUR SPINE,
AND CAUSE THE PARALYSIS.
IT'S A DISEASE CALLED
TRANSVERSE MYELITIS.
AND IS THAT GOOD NEWS
OR BAD NEWS?
IT'S GREAT NEWS.
I'LL GET YOU A ROOM
AND START YOU ON ACYCLOVIR.
I JUST HAD A HOUSE MOMENT.
DIAGNOSED TRANSVERSE MYELITIS
FROM A COLD SORE.
HOW COOL IS THAT?
PATIENTS REALLY EAT
THAT CRAP UP.
IT'S WHY I'M LOVED.
WHAT AM I DOING HERE?
(Thirteen)
ULTRASOUND IS CLEAR.
WHICH MEANS HE'S DEFINITELY
NOT PREGNANT, RIGHT?
DIOS MIO, MI ESTOMAGO!
NO GALL STONES.
COULD BE DIVERTICULITIS.
HAVE YOU EATEN
ANY SEEDS?
(patient)
I'M JOINING YOU,
ANTONIO AGUILAR.
WE'LL PLAY IN GOD'S
MARIACHI BAND.
DRAW SOME BLOOD.
THE SELF-IMPORTANT JERK
DOES NOT HAVE
TRANSVERSE MYELITIS.
HE'S GOT CANCER.
HOW DO YOU EVEN--
OKAY.
MAYBE I PAID THE REDHEAD
DOWN IN RECORDS A FEW BUCKS
TO CC ME
ON ALL YOUR CASES.
A FEW PATIENTS DIE,
YOU MIGHT GET SAD AGAIN.
MAKE A SPEECH
THAT WOULD END YOUR CAREER.
FRANKLY,
I'M STALKING YOU FOR YOU.
HOW LONG DOES A SIMPLE
BLOOD DRAW TAKE?
ALMOST FINISHED.
WELL,
WHEN YOU'RE FINISHED
ALMOST FINISHING IT,
TEST IT.
MI ESTOMAGO'SRIPPED OPEN
BY THE HAND OF GOD.
HE SPILLED MY BLOOD.
CONFUSION. DELIRIUM.
WHY RULE OUT
THE HAND OF GOD SO FAST?
YOUR GUY'S LOW WHITE COUNT
AND RIGHT ARM PARALYSIS
EQUALS A RECURRENCE
OF HIS LEUKEMIA.
SIMPLE MATH.
DID YOU LOOK PAST
THE FIRST PAGE
OF THE FILE?
NO AML CELLS ANYWHERE.
I DID THE BLOOD SMEARS
MYSELF.
IT'S STILL CANCER.
YOU KNOW HOW I KNOW?
HE'S GOT AN ONCOLOGIST
FOR A DOCTOR.
AND YOUR MAGICAL
LEUKEMIA DETECTOR
IS MORE POWERFUL
THAN A FLOW CYTOMETER?
I LOOK FOR ZEBRAS
BECAUSE OTHER DOCTORS
RULE OUT ALL THE HORSES.
IN THIS CASE,
YOU ARE THOSE OTHER DOCTORS.
YOU HAVEN'T EARNED
A ZEBRA.
100 BUCKS.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
LOOK, FRIENDS DON'T DIAGNOSE
FRIENDS WITH CANCER.
I GET IT.
YOUR PROBLEM IS
YOU'RE NOT OBJECTIVE.
YOUR CARING IS CLOUDING
YOUR DIAGNOSIS.
JUST CUT THAT OUT
AND YOU COULD BE
A PRETTY DECENT DOCTOR.
JUST GIVE ME
THE LACTIC ACID LEVEL.
27.
[inhales]
THE FACT THAT YOU CAN'T
SPEAK ENGLISH
IS NOT AN EXCUSE
FOR YOU NOT BEING HUMILIATED
BY WHAT I'M ABOUT TO SAY.
IT'S ALSO NOT AN EXCUSE
FOR YOU NOT TELLING US
THAT YOU WERE A TENNIS PRO.
IF YOU HAD, WE WOULDN'T
HAVE WASTED OUR TIME.
FINE.
100 BUCKS.
[patient screams]
IS TUCKER SETTLING IN?
YEAH. ALREADY GOT
HIS FIRST DOSE OF ACYCLOVIR.
AND DON'T WORRY,
I ORDERED HIS GIRLFRIEND
THE KIDDY MEAL.
HOO-AH.
NEXT PATIENT ON DECK.
DEL CLINTON.
DAY SIX OF CHEMO.
YOU JUST MISSED
THE GRANDKIDS.
OH, THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
LAST TIME THEY WERE HERE,
THEY PAINTED MY TIE.
YOU'RE ALMOST READY
TO GO HOME.
YOU FEELING OKAY?
I FEEL LIKE I FELT
AFTER THE LAST FOUR ROUNDS.
IN ONCOLOGY, FAMILIAR PAIN
MEANS ALL IS WELL.
SO THAT'S GOOD, RIGHT?
YEAH.
[pager sounds]
I HEARD JESSE AND ZEKE
WERE BY EARLIER.
YEAH.
SORRY, DEL, I GOTTA RUN.
HOW ARE THEY DOING?
THEY--THEY'RE FINE.
NO GAME-WINNING HITS?
NO ACED REPORT CARDS?
NO SCHOOL PLAYS?
I GUESS NOT.
I THOUGHT YOU HAD TO GO.
ARE YOU DEPRESSED?
I HAVE CANCER.
YOU'VE HAD CANCER
FOR A LONG TIME.
IT'S NEVER STOPPED YOU
FROM BRAGGING
ABOUT THE GRANDKIDS.
I GUESS I'M FEELING A LITTLE
MORE DOWN THAN USUAL.
CAN YOU GIVE ME SOMETHING?
YEAH. I DON'T WANT YOU
TO GET ALARMED,
BUT SOMETIMES DEPRESSION
CAN BE A SIGN
THAT SOMETHING ELSE
IS GOING ON.
I'M JUST GONNA ORDER
A COUPLE OF EXTRA TESTS.
OKAY?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
IT'S HIS FOOT NOW.
IT'S NOTHING.
IT'S NOT NOTHING.
I JUST STARTED GETTING
A LITTLE TINGLING FEELING
IN MY FOOT.
IS THAT BAD?
ASHLEY,
IT'S GONNA BE OKAY.
IT MIGHT MEAN HIS FOOT
FELL ASLEEP.
IT MIGHT MEAN NOTHING.
COULD YOU GIVE US
A FEW MINUTES?
WHAT--WHY CAN'T YOU
TELL ME?
BECAUSE
YOU'RE MAKING HIM NERVOUS.
JUST GIVE US A FEW MINUTES,
OKAY, HON?
DOES THIS MEAN
THAT IT'S NOT THE DISEASE
YOU THOUGHT IT WAS?
IT MEANS THE MEDICINE
I GAVE YOU IS NOT WORKING.
I JUST MIGHT HAVE
TO HIT IT HARDER.
I'M GOING TO ADD RIBAVIRIN
TO YOUR TREATMENT.
JIM.
ARE YOU SURE THAT
THIS ISN'T A RECURRENCE?
SO THE BRAVE FACE
IS JUST FOR ASHLEY.
SHE'S YOUNG.
SHE'S TERRIFIED.
SHE'S NOT REALLY
EQUIPPED.
DON'T WORRY.
ONCE YOU'VE HAD CANCER,
RECURRENCE IS YOUR BIGGEST FEAR.
I GET IT.
I'VE LOOKED AT THIS THING
EVERY WHICH WAY THERE IS.
THAT'S NOT
WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE.
CAN YOU CALL MY DAUGHTER
AND ASK HER TO COME DOWN?
YOU CAN'T DO IT?
SHE HASN'T EXACTLY
BEEN TALKING TO ME
SINCE I GOT TOGETHER
WITH ASHLEY.
I'D REALLY LIKE HER
TO BE HERE.
OF COURSE.
EXACTLY HOW SERIOUS
DOES IT HAVE TO BE
TO JUSTIFY YOU COMING
TO SEE YOUR FATHER?
NO. I'M SORRY.
I JUST--I'D RATHER
YOU REGRETTED COMING
THAN REGRETTED NOT COMING.
THANKS, EMILY.
HOW'S TUCKER?
OH, WELL, HE'S MADE A MESS
OF HIS PERSONAL LIFE.
BUT PHYSICALLY,
I THINK HE'S GONNA BE FINE.
TRANSVERSE MYELITIS.
WHAT DOES HOUSE THINK?
WHAT IS THIS?
IS HOUSE MY OVERSEER NOW?
NO, IT'S JUST NOT ALWAYS
A GOOD IDEA
FOR DOCTORS TO TREAT
THEIR FRIENDS,
THAT'S ALL.
WELL, HOUSE HAS GOT
100 BUCKS ON CANCER.
SO UNLESS YOU WANT IN
ON THE ACTION...
UM, IS BONNIE
STILL A REALTOR?
AS FAR AS I KNOW.
DO YOU MIND
IF I CALL HER?
I'M, UH, LOOKING
FOR A NEW PLACE.
I'M MOVING IN WITH LUCAS.
(Taub)
IT WASN'T THE TENNIS.
YOU'RE MOVING IN
WITH LUCAS?
YES.
YOU'RE BONNIE'S FRIEND.
YOU KNOW
HOW TO REACH HER.
AND YET INSTEAD
OF CALLING HER,
YOU COME AND SEEK
MY PERMISSION.
YOU WANT MY BLESSING,
AND IMPLICITLY,
HOUSE'S BLESSING.
I DON'T NEED
GOOD.
SO WHEN WILL HE BE ABLE
TO MOVE HIS ARM AGAIN?
SHOULD BE SOON.
[coughs]
STARTED SMOKING AGAIN?
[coughs] NO.
WHAT--WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
IS IT BAD THAT HE'S COUGHING?
HI, DAD.
HEY.
MELISSA, HEY.
[clears throat]
I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU WERE COMING.
I WAS AT MOM'S HOUSE
WHEN DR. WILSON CALLED.
I CAN GO
IF IT'S GONNA BE WEIRD.
[coughs] NO, NO. STAY.
IT'S FINE.
HI.
HOW ARE YOU?
IS HE OKAY?
YEAH. HE'S OKAY.
I'M NOT A BIG FAN
OF THIS COUGHING THOUGH.
YOU MUST BE ASHLEY.
HI.
[coughs]
HEY, ARE YOU OKAY?
[gasping]
DO YOU THINK
THIS COLD SORE THING
COULD'VE CAUSED THIS?
NO. WHATEVER'S CAUSING THIS
IS AFFECTING MORE THAN
HIS NERVES.
I NEED A CRASH CART
IN HERE!
[coughing and gasping]
DON'T YOU GUYS HAVE
A DYING MEXICAN CROONER
TO ATTEND TO?
HE ISN'T DYING ANYMORE.
FOUND OUT
HE WAS ON A POPCORN DIET.
EATING TEN BAGS
OF MICROWAVE POPCORN A DAY.
HUFFING THE FUMES
SCARED HIS LUNGS.
WOW, THAT'S...
VERY STRANGE.
WHERE'S HOUSE?
PERFORMING HIS RITUAL
"HIDING FROM CUDDY
TO AVOID GETTING
A NEW CASE" DANCE.
IT'S SORT OF A JAZZ-FUSION
TYPE OF THING.
HE'S PROBABLY EATING LUNCH
IN THE MORGUE.
I CAN PAGE HIM TO YOUR OFFICE
IF YOU WANT.
ACTUALLY...
MAYBE IT WOULD BE BETTER
IF I TALKED TO YOU GUYS ALONE.
HOUSE AND I HAVE A BET
ABOUT ONE OF MY PATIENTS.
YOU GUYS MIND MAKING HIM
100 BUCKS POORER?
43-YEAR-OLD MALE
IN REMISSION FROM LEUKEMIA
PRESENTS WITH LEFT ARM PARALYSIS
AND TROUBLE BREATHING.
I ASSUME HOUSE'S MONEY
IS ON CANCER.
THANKS.
THAT'S VERY HELPFUL.
SUBDURAL HEMATOMA
WOULD EXPLAIN--
CT RULED IT OUT.
I THOUGHT IT WAS TM
SO I STARTED HIM ON ANTIVIRALS,
BUT HE GOT WORSE.
BACTERIAL INFECTION?
BACTERIA WOULD MOVE
MUCH FASTER THAN THIS.
HE'D BE DEAD ALREADY.
COULD BE FUNGAL.
FUNGAL INFECTION WOULD EXPLAIN
HIS BREATHING PROBLEM,
BUT NOT HIS "UNABLE TO MOVE
HIS ARM" PROBLEM.
ACTUALLY,
IF ASPERGILLUS FUNGUS BALLS
TOOK ROOT IN HIS LUNGS
AND SPREAD TO HIS SPINE,
IT WOULD EXPLAIN BOTH.
THANKS.
THE TREATMENT INVOLVES RIDDLING
THE INFECTED AREA
WITH BB-SIZED PELLETS
OF ANTIFUNGAL MEDS.
I ASSUME YOU DON'T JUST
LOAD UP THE 12-GAUGE
AND PEPPER ME
WITH BIRDSHOT.
NO. WE HAVE A SLIGHTLY
MORE HUMANE DELIVERY SYSTEM.
BUT WE DO HAVE TO OPEN YOU UP.
IT IS SURGERY.
AND LIKE ANY OPERATION,
THERE ARE RISKS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
HONEY?
I-I DON'T KNOW.
I MEAN, IS SURGERY
REALLY SUCH A GOOD IDEA?
HE JUST SEEMS SO SICK.
I JUST--
YOU SHOULD DO
WHATEVER YOU THINK IS BEST.
IS THIS THE ONLY WAY
TO GO AFTER THIS THING?
BECAUSE OF THE RAPID
PROGRESSION,
I DON'T THINK WE HAVE TIME
TO TEST OR TRY IVs.
AND HE'S STRONG ENOUGH
TO ENDURE ANESTHESIA.
DEFINITELY.
I WANT YOU THERE
DURING THE SURGERY.
OF COURSE.
YOU GOTTA DO IT.
GOOD. DR. CHASE
WILL BE IN HERE SOON
TO GET YOU SET FOR THE O.R.
PAGE DR. CHASE TO TUCKER'S ROOM
FOR A SURGERY CONSULT.
AND CAN YOU GET ME--
UH, MR. KOPLOVITZ WANTS
TO TALK TO YOU.
IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
HE WANTED TO TALK
TO HIS DOCTOR,
NOT HIS DOCTOR'S ASSISTANT.
OH, AND HOUSE IS LOOKING
FOR YOU.
WHAT DID YOU TELL HIM?
THAT YOU WERE
IN THE CLINIC.
I FIGURE THAT GIVES YOU
ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
HERE.
MR. KOPLOVITZ'S CHART. GO.
HELLO, SAUL.
I HEARD YOU WERE LOOKING
FOR ME.
I'M VERY TIRED.
BUT I CAN'T SLEEP.
TODAY'S YOUR LUCKY DAY.
I HAPPEN TO BE
A SLEEP SPECIALIST.
THANKS, DOC.
[toilet flushes]
HEY. CAN A GUY GET
A LITTLE PRIVACY?
NICE HIDING SPOT.
ACTUALLY, IT'S PERFECT.
IT ALLOWS ME TO HIDE FROM CUDDY
AND FIND YOU.
WHAT DID SHE WANT?
SHE WAS CHECKING UP ON TUCKER
THANKS TO YOU.
THAT'S IT?
LIKE WHAT?
SOMETHING ABOUT YOU?
SOMETHING YOU COULD INTERPRET
AS BEING ABOUT YOU?
AN ANAGRAM MAYBE?
IT'D BE GREAT IF YOU COULD PLAY
HIDE AND SEEK SOMEWHERE ELSE.
MY PATIENT JUST--
NO PROBLEM.
JUST GIVE ME THE 100 BUCKS
YOU OWE ME AND I'M GONE.
TUCKER DOESN'T HAVE CANCER.
HE DOESN'T HAVE
A BALL OF FUNGUS
IN HIS LUNGS EITHER.
NEXT TIME YOU WANT
TO USE MY TEAM,
I SUGGEST
YOU AT LEAST LEAVE A TIP.
I'M LATE FOR SURGERY.
AH, YOUR ASSISTANT SAID
YOU'D BE IN HERE.
I TALKED TO BONNIE.
LET'S TAKE THIS OUTSIDE.
MR. KOPLOVITZ
JUST GOT TO SLEEP.
OH, SORRY. SHE FOUND US
THIS FANTASTIC LOFT.
OUTSIDE.
I MEAN,
IT'S NOT A LOFT REALLY,
IT'S JUST MORE URBAN.
NOT THAT I'M URBAN,
BUT I USED TO BE.
IT'S GOT TWO BEDROOMS.
GOT WONDERFUL VIEWS.
IT'S A REALLY GREAT PLACE.
PROCEDURE SHOULD TAKE
ABOUT AN HOUR.
I'LL BE OBSERVING
THE ENTIRE TIME.
THANKS.
MAYBE IT'D BE BETTER
IF YOU STAYED WITH ASHLEY.
SHE'S MORE SCARED
THAN I AM.
[chuckles]
WELL, SHE'S...
AT HER AGE...
SHE'S NOT SUPPOSED TO BE DEALING
WITH ISSUES OF LIFE AND DEATH.
WASN'T WHAT I WAS PLANNING
WHEN I WENT AFTER HER.
WHY DID YOU LEAVE MELISSA?
WE GOT MARRIED YOUNG.
WE...
I'M NOT SURE.
[door opens]
THERE'S NOTHING
TO TALK ABOUT.
WHY ARE YOU DOING SURGERY
WHEN I NEED YOU
FINDING ME A NEW CASE?
YOU DON'T WANT
A NEW CASE.
OH, RIGHT.
GUESS I'M HERE FOR WILSON.
OBVIOUSLY
YOU DIDN'T TELL ME
THAT CUDDY WAS MOVING IN
WITH LUCAS
'CAUSE YOU WERE
PROTECTING ME.
WHICH IS ODD
SINCE I TOLD YOU
THAT I'M FINE
WITH THEIR RELATIONSHIP.
SO OBVIOUSLY,
YOU QUESTION
ONE OF THOSE ASSUMPTIONS
OR YOU HAVE AN ISSUE
WITH LOGIC.
YES, YOU'RE FINE
WITH THEM DATING.
BUT MOVING IN TOGETHER
IS A WHOLE OTHER LEVEL
OF COMMITMENT.
[scoffs] THIS IS
THE 21ST CENTURY, WILSON.
I REALIZE
THAT THE LOGICAL COURSE
OF ANY ADULT RELATIONSHIP
COULD ONE DAY LEAD
TO FORNICATION.
ALTHOUGH, THE FACT
THAT SHE WANTS TO BUY A LOFT
COULD ACTUALLY MEAN
THAT THEIR RELATIONSHIP
IS NOT AS SERIOUS
AS I THOUGHT.
OH, FOR GOD'S SAKE,
HOUSE,
DON'T DO THIS TO YOURSELF.
IT'S A LOFT.
IT HAS NO DEEPER MEANING
THAN OPEN-SPACE
LIVING ARRANGEMENT.
IF YOU BOUGHT
INTO HER DIATRIBE
ABOUT REDISCOVERING
HER LOST CITY GIRL ROOTS.
AND TWO BEDROOMS.
IT JUST REEKS
OF COMMITMENT ISSUES.
YEAH. OR SHE HAS A BABY.
THIS IS CLASSIC
MID-LIFE CUDDY CRISIS.
THIS IS HER VERSION
OF A TWO-SEAT CONVERTIBLE.
YEAH, CLEARLY YOU'RE FINE
WITH IT.
(Chase)
WILSON, HE'S GOT GLOBAL
LUNG DAMAGE.
MEANS IT'S NOT FUNGAL.
IT'S PCP PNEUMONIA.
HMM.
OBVIOUSLY SOMETHING
IS KNOCKING OUT
HIS IMMUNE SYSTEM.
THREE OPTIONS.
HIV. ACQUIRED SCID.
OR MY PERSONAL FAVORITE,
CANCER.
I'M SURE YOU'LL TEST
FOR ALL THREE.
62-YEAR-OLD
AFRICAN-AMERICAN MAN
WITH LYMPHOMA
NOW IN REMISSION.
I DID A CT AND FOUND
A SMALL LESION
ON THE UPPER LOBE
OF HIS LEFT LUNG.
IF HE'S IN REMISSION,
WHY DID YOU BOTHER
SCANNING HIM?
DURING A ROUTINE FOLLOW-UP,
I REALIZED THE PATIENT
WAS DEPRESSED.
WOW.
THAT'S QUITE A CALL.
THANKS.
THE TREATMENT INDICATE--
[door opens]
OH, I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T REALIZE YOU WERE
IN THE MIDDLE OF SOMETHING.
IT'S A CONFERENCE ROOM
WITH GLASS WALLS.
YOU THOUGHT I'D BE ALONE?
YOUR PATIENT HAS CANCER.
NOT THAT GUY.
HE PROBABLY ALSO
HAS CANCER.
AND HE'S PROBABLY ALSO
YOUR BUDDY.
THOUGHT YOU'D WANT
TO KNOW.
'CAUSE YOU OWE ME
100 BUCKS.
LYMPHOBLASTIC LEUKEMIA.
A.L.L.
SO IT IS
A RECURRENCE.
NO. IT'S DIFFERENT.
IT'S A SECOND LEUKEMIA.
PROBABLY CAUSED
BY THE CHEMOTHERAPY
WE GAVE HIM
FIVE YEARS AGO.
THAT'S WHY YOU DIDN'T
SEE IT.
MAYBE THEY CAN RENAME IT
IRONIC LEUKEMIA.
THIS IS NOT THE END.
TESTS SHOW THAT THE CANCER
IS LIMITED TO YOUR BRAIN.
THAT'S GOOD NEWS.
HOW CAN CANCER IN HIS HEAD
BE GOOD NEWS?
THE BLOOD BRAIN BARRIER
SEPARATES
THE BLOOD IN YOUR HEAD
FROM THE BLOOD IN YOUR BODY.
KEEPS THE CANCER
BOTTLED UP.
WE CAN GO FOR A CURE.
SO GIVE ME THE NUMBERS.
WHAT ARE WE LOOKING AT?
90% CHANCE OF CURE.
REALLY?
WHAT IF WE'RE IN THE 10%?
STEADY DECLINE.
BUT SIX MONTHS
OF A GOOD QUALITY LIFE.
(Emily)
DOES HE HAVE TO GO THROUGH
ANOTHER BONE MARROW
TRANSPLANT?
NO.
CHEMOTHERAPY.
WE CAN GO AT THIS
WITH DRUGS ALONE.
WHEN DO WE GET STARTED?
WE BEGIN BY SURGICALLY
PLANTING A SHUNT
SO WE CAN GET THE DRUGS
DIRECTLY INTO YOUR BRAIN.
I ALREADY BOOKED THE O.R.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN MAKE CANCER
SOUND LIKE GOOD NEWS.
WE GET IT OUT OF YOUR HEAD
AND YOU WALK OUT OF HERE
PARALYSIS GONE
AND CANCER-FREE.
WE ALSO NEED YOU TO SIGN
A HEALTH CARE PROXY.
IF SOMETHING GOES WRONG
IN SURGERY,
SOMEONE NEEDS TO BE APPOINTED
TO MAKE DECISIONS FOR YOU.
WHAT ARE THE CHANCES
OF THAT HAPPENING?
VERY REMOTE.
I THINK MAYBE MELISSA
SHOULD BE MY PROXY.
WHAT?
NO.
(Foreman)
COMING THROUGH.
HOUSE GOT A NEW CASE.
REVISED O.R. SCHEDULE.
SORRY, WILSON, HAD TO BUMP YOU.
IT'S NOT LIKE YOUR GUY'S
BLEEDING OUT OF HIS EYES.
HOUSE, YOUR GUY'S NOT BLEEDING
OUT OF HIS EYES EITHER.
THE NURSE WHO BOOKS THE O.R.
THINKS HE IS.
YOUR CASE IS NO MORE URGENT
THAN MINE.
YEAH, BUT YOU'RE WAY
MORE PATIENT.
IT'S OKAY.
YOU CAN TALK
ABOUT THE--THE PAPERWORK
IN THE PREP AREA.
YOU TRUST HER MORE
THAN ME.
ABOUT THIS, YES.
[clears throat]
YOU'VE BEEN THROUGH
THE GOOD STUFF,
BUT MELISSA'S BEEN
TO HELL AND BACK WITH ME.
SHE GIVES ME THE BEST SHOT
OF GETTING THROUGH THIS.
YOU STILL LOVE HER.
DON'T BE SILLY.
I LOVE YOU.
PLEASE...
DON'T MAKE THIS
INTO MORE THAN IT IS.
OKAY, ANYTHING?
NO.
CAN YOU FEEL THIS?
HOW ABOUT HERE?
NO.
WHERE IS EVERYBODY?
MELISSA AND EMILY
WENT DOWNSTAIRS
TO GET SOME BREAKFAST.
ASHLEY?
SHE HAD WORK TO DO.
I THOUGHT SHE WAS OFF TODAY.
WELL, SHE DIDN'T REALLY
HAVE WORK TO DO.
SHE WAS JUST PISSED
SO SHE PRETENDED
TO HAVE WORK TO DO.
I LET HER PRETEND.
OKAY.
MOVE YOUR FINGERS.
THE CHEMO'S NOT WORKING.
DOES THAT MEAN
IT'S NOT CANCER?
NO. IT MEANS THE CHEMO
FROM YOUR FIRST ROUND
OF TREATMENT
HAS MADE THE LEUKEMIA
RESISTANT.
SO I'M IN THE 10%
THAT DON'T GET CURED.
MAYBE NOT.
WE JUST REMOVED A SCREW
FROM A GUY'S LUNG.
AND THE WEIRD THING IS
HE DIDN'T GET BETTER.
ANY IDEA WHAT THAT MEANS?
IT MEANS
YOU'RE NOT LISTENING TO ME.
NO. IT MEANS I'M IGNORING YOU
TO MAKE A POINT.
THERE IS A DIFFERENCE.
THE PROBLEM
WITH THAT TECHNIQUE
IS I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT POINT YOU'RE MAKING.
THAT YOUR IDEA IS IMPLICITLY
NOT WORTH RESPONDING TO.
DOUBLING YOUR PATIENT'S
CHEMO DOSE IS STUPID.
DAMN. NOW IT'S EXPLICIT.
IT COULD SWAMP OUT
THE RESISTANCE
OF THE CANCER CELLS.
THE FACT THAT IT
THEORETICALLY SHOULD WORK
DOESN'T MAKE IT
ANY LESS STUPID.
OF COURSE IT DOES.
IT'S EXACTLY WHAT YOU WOULD DO.
I'M ME. YOU'RE YOU.
AND A TABLE IS A TABLE.
AND CHEMO IS POISON.
AND DOUBLE CHEMO
IS DOUBLE POISON.
I CAN HANDLE IT
WHEN THINGS GO WRONG.
YOU CAN'T.
AND THINGS COULD GO VERY,
VERY WRONG.
I CAN HANDLE IT.
SOUNDS PRETTY DANGEROUS.
IT IS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK, MEL?
I THINK
YOU SHOULD CALL ASHLEY.
YOU'RE MY FAMILY.
I'M SORRY I FORGOT THAT.
I THINK
THAT YOU SHOULD TRY
WHATEVER COULD KEEP YOU
WITH US LONGER.
YEAH.
[chattering and laughter]
LOOK.
I CAN MOVE THEM.
HEY!
THANK YOU.
[laughs]
WHAT IS IT, JIM?
I'M GONNA NEED TO RUN
SOME TESTS.
INTRAEPIDERMAL
SUPERFICIAL BULLAE.
COULD BE PEMPHIGUS.
OR IT COULD BE
FROM THE FIRE.
EITHER WAY, HE'S DEAD.
WE CAN'T STOP
THE OOZING.
DON'T CARE.
I'M HERE BECAUSE IT'S 1:15
AND WILSON STARTED TESTING
AT 12:45.
WHICH MEANS...
THE CANCER'S GONE.
BUT OVER HALF HIS HEPATOCYTES
ARE DEAD.
IN ONLY 24 HOURS?
HE NEEDS A NEW LIVER.
LOOK ON THE BRIGHT SIDE.
YOU CAN PUBLISH THE RESULTS
OF THIS CASE STUDY.
NO ONE WILL EVER DOUBLE
THE DOSE AGAIN.
GOT RID OF YOUR CANCER.
BUT IT ALSO TRASHED
YOUR LIVER.
IF I DON'T FIND YOU
A NEW LIVER,
YOU'VE ONLY GOT
ABOUT 24 HOURS LEFT.
SO WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
YOUR FATHER'S BEEN MOVED
TO THE TOP
OF THE TRANSPLANT LIST.
BUT ALL WE REALLY
CAN DO IS WAIT.
THAT'S IT? WE WAIT?
TELL ME SOMETHING
THAT I CAN DO.
I'M SORRY, MEL.
YOU AND EMILY DON'T MATCH
TUCK'S BLOOD TYPE.
AND NEITHER DOES ASHLEY.
SO A LIVE LIVER DONATION
IS OUT.
THE BEST THING TO DO
IS JUST WHAT YOU'VE BEEN DOING.
BE TOGETHER.
HOPE HE ALREADY TOLD YOU
THAT YOU'RE GONNA DIE.
'CAUSE IT'S GONNA MAKE
WHAT I'M ABOUT TO SAY
A LOT MORE RELEVANT.
HOUSE, I KNOW IT'S RAINING
OUT THERE IN THE HALLWAY,
BUT--
I WAS JUST IN THE ER
TESTING MY PATIENT
FOR AUTONOMIC DYSFUNCTION.
IT'S THE ONLY DEPARTMENT
WITH A SHOWER BIG ENOUGH
FOR THE WHOLE TEAM,
PLUS THE CARDIAC MONITORS,
PLUS ME.
ANYWAY, RELEVANT PART,
WE'RE JUST WHEELING
THE GUY OUT,
TRAUMA CAME IN.
MOTORCYCLE VERSUS SEMI.
HOW BAD?
BAD FOR THE MOTORCYCLE.
GOOD FOR YOUR LIVER.
BLOOD TYPE'S A MATCH.
WHY WASN'T I PAGED?
BECAUSE THERE'S A PROBLEM.
NO ORGAN DONOR CARD.
DEAD GUY'S SISTER
IS NEXT OF KIN.
SHE'S REFUSING TO ALLOW
THE DONATION.
WHERE IS SHE?
20 MINUTES AWAY.
HOW DO YOU GET THE CALL
THAT YOUR BROTHER'S DEAD
AND THEN RUN OUT THE DOOR?
"OH--OH--OH,
THAT REMINDS ME,
I-I HAD DRY CLEANING
TO PICK UP."
DID CUDDY BUY THE PLACE?
NOT YET. YOU OKAY?
JUST MAKING CONVERSATION.
YOURS WAS GETTING BORING.
WHAT ARE YOU PLANNING?
I'M NOT PLANNING ANYTHING.
AND I DON'T BELIEVE YOU.
HOW ARE YOU GONNA PUNISH HER
FOR DATING LUCAS?
OKAY, NOW THIS CONVERSATION
IS GETTING BORING.
ARE YOU REALLY OKAY?
NO!
I AM NOT OKAY.
NOT EVEN CLOSE.
WOW. OKAY.
SEE, THAT'S VERY ADULT OF YOU.
NO, IT ISN'T.
IT'S JUST ME ACCEPTING
THE FACT
THAT THERE'S NOTHING I CAN DO
AND MOVING ON.
WHICH IS, I THINK,
THE DEFINITION OF ADULTHOOD.
WELL, IF IT IS,
BEING A KID IS A LOT MORE FUN.
SHOWTIME.
I DIDN'T SPEAK TO HIM
FOR YEARS.
BUT WHEN MY PARENTS DIED,
AT THEIR FUNERAL,
WE MADE PEACE.
OUR PARENTS
MUST'VE BLESSED IT.
AND I'M SURE THEY WOULD
WANT HIM TO DO GOOD
WITH HIS LAST ACT
IN THIS WORLD.
THEY WANTED US
TO BE FRIENDS.
OUR RELATIONSHIP
WASN'T STRONG,
BUT IT WAS GROWING.
IF I ALLOW YOU
TO DEFILE HIS BODY,
IT WILL DESTROY
THAT BOND.
THEITAIWILL BE HARMED.
IT WILL SAVE
MY PATIENT'S LIFE.
WHAT IF I TOLD YOU
THAT HE WASN'T DEAD?
ARE YOU SAYING MY BROTHER
IS STILL ALIVE?
I'M SAYING YOU'RE BEING
AN IDIOT.
BUT I DON'T HAVE TIME
TO TALK YOU OUT
OF YOUR RELIGION
SO I'M STUCK WITH GIVING YOU
A TECHNICALITY
THAT WILL LET YOU JUSTIFY
DOING THE RIGHT THING.
WHAT IF HIS LAST
LIVING ACT
WAS TO DONATE A PART
OF HIS LIVER?
[pager sounds]
NOT THE WHOLE THING,
JUST ONE SMALL PIECE.
THEN I'M NOT DEFILING
A DEAD BODY.
HOUSE.
THE LAST GENEROUS ACT
OF A LIVING PERSON.
HOUSE, IT'S TOO LATE.
THE LIVER STARTED
TO DEGRADE.
IT'S NO LONGER VIABLE
FOR TRANSPLANT.
WELL PLAYED.
RELIGION JUST KILLED
ANOTHER PERSON.
IT'S NOT FAIR, JIM.
YOU JUST HELPED ME
GET MY FAMILY BACK TOGETHER.
I'M--I'M NOT READY.
[woman sniffles]
I WOULD'VE HAD SIX MORE MONTHS
WITH THEM
IF YOU HADN'T GIVEN ME
THAT EXTRA CHEMO.
NOW I HAVE LESS
THAN ONE DAY.
I'M SORRY.
WE KNEW THE RISKS.
I DON'T WANT
TO LOSE THEM AGAIN.
I CAN'T LOSE THEM AGAIN.
THERE'S NOTHING MORE
WE CAN DO.
FIVE YEARS AGO,
WHEN I NEEDED A TRANSFUSION,
YOU USED YOUR OWN BLOOD.
WE HAVE THE SAME TYPE.
WHICH MEANS YOU CAN GIVE ME
A PART OF YOUR LIVER.
I'M YOUR DOCTOR.
YOU'RE MY FRIEND.
SHOULD I DIE BECAUSE
YOU'RE ALSO MY DOCTOR?
OF COURSE NOT.
FINE THEN. YOU'RE FIRED.
NOW YOU'RE JUST MY FRIEND.
NOW YOU CAN DO WHAT'S RIGHT.
TUCKER, IT'S...
I CAN'T.
[sportscaster announcing
game results]
LATE NIGHT
WITH THE PIGEON SISTERS?
[sportscaster announcing
game results]
EVERY NOW AND AGAIN,
I'D LIKE TO COME HOME
WITHOUT GETTING
INTERROGATED.
[sportscaster announcing
game results]
SOMEONE'S CRANKY.
AND LATE.
WHERE WERE YOU?
JUST GETTING A DRINK.
WHAT--WHY ARE ALL
MY FROZEN DINNERS
THAWING ON THE COUNTER?
I NEEDED ROOM
FOR MY MARGARITA JELL-O SHOTS.
I USE TEST TUBES AS BOTTLES
SO THEY'LL BE SHAPED
LIKE MY CANE.
[shuts off TV]
WHY'D YOU GO OUT
DRINKING ALONE
WHEN YOU GOT SUCH
GREAT COMPANY HERE?
TUCKER WANTS ME TO DONATE
A LOBE OF MY LIVER TO HIM.
AND YOU WERE OUT DRINKING.
SO YOU'RE ACTUALLY
CONSIDERING THIS?
YEAH. I WAS OUT MARINATING
MY LIVER IN ALCOHOL
TO GET IT READY
FOR THE TRANSPLANT. YEAH.
YOUR MOUTH SAYS NO,
BUT YOUR PATHETIC ATTEMPT
AT A DEFLECTION
HAS GUILT WRITTEN
ALL OVER IT.
IT'S MY FAULT.
IT IS MY FAULT!
I GAVE HIM TOO MUCH CHEMO.
YOU CURED HIS CANCER.
AND KILLED HIM
IN THE PROCESS.
QUIBBLES.
[laughs]
HE'S HAD
A PREDICTABLE COMPLICATION.
SURPRISE. BAD THINGS HAPPEN
TO PEOPLE WHO ARE SICK.
DOESN'T MAKE YOU
RESPONSIBLE.
OH, NO--NOT LEGALLY.
ETHICALLY.
ETHICALLY!
A TABLE IS A TABLE.
DON'T BE A DOORMAT,
WILSON.
BOY, YOU ARE--
YOU WILLFULLY RUINED MY FOOD
AND HAVE TAKEN OVER
MY LIVING ROOM
BECAUSE YOU ALREADY THINK
I'M A DOORMAT!
YOU KNOW WHAT...
YOU'RE WRONG.
YOU--CLEAN UP YOUR STUFF
AND GET OUT.
[smacks doorframe]
YOU'RE WRONG. [slams door]
HOW'S TUCKER?
UM, STILL NOT DANCING.
BUT SCANS CAME IN
ON DEL CLINTON.
IT'S GOOD NEWS.
THANKS.
LET ME KNOW AS SOON AS TUCKER
TAKES A TURN FOR THE WORSE.
I WANT TO BE THERE.
SEE THAT SMALL SPOT
AT THE TOP OF THE LUNG?
THAT WAS THEN.
THIS IS NOW.
SPOT'S GONE.
THAT TINY LITTLE SPOT,
HUH?
YEAH.
IT'S NOT TOO IMPRESSIVE,
IS IT?
THAT LITTLE DOT
COULD'VE KILLED ME?
YEAH.
FORTUNATELY,
WE CAUGHT IT EARLY.
IT'S GONNA BE OKAY.
THAT'S AMAZING.
YOU GOT ALL THIS OFF ME
NOT TALKING ABOUT MY GRANDKIDS.
THANKS, BONNIE.
JUST GONNA HAVE
TO SIT TIGHT
FOR AWHILE.
OKAY. [hangs up]
I PUT AN OFFER
ON THE LOFT.
SELLER TURNED ME DOWN.
I OFFERED EXACTLY
WHAT A SIMILAR UNIT
SOLD FOR THREE MONTHS AGO.
I WANT TO DONATE A LOBE
OF MY LIVER TO TUCKER.
THAT'S INSANE.
I'M DONATING
A SMALL PORTION OF--
YOU HAVE HUNDREDS
OF PATIENTS.
AND UNTIL I RUN OUT
OF EXCESS ORGANS,
WHY SHOULDN'T I DO EVERYTHING
I CAN TO HELP THEM?
BECAUSE YOU'RE A DOCTOR,
NOT A DONOR.
[laughs]
WHY DID YOU MAKE ME
THE HEAD OF ONCOLOGY?
NOT BECAUSE YOU HAVE
THE MOST ORGANS.
YOU'RE THOUGHTFUL,
CARING.
YEAH, CARING.
BY YOUR OWN CRITERIA
A STRENGTH AND NOT A WEAKNESS.
THIS IS COMING OUT OF GUILT.
THIS IS COMING OUT
OF FRIENDSHIP.
I HAVE A FRIEND
WHO'S ABOUT TO DIE.
AND I HAVE THE OPPORTUNITY
TO SAVE HIS LIFE.
OKAY.
CALL ME A DOORMAT--
GET IT ALL OUT OF YOUR SYSTEM--
BUT I'M DOING IT.
WHY?
HE'S MY FRIEND.
I'M YOUR FRIEND.
ALL THE PAIN PILLS
I'VE TAKEN.
WHAT IF I NEED YOUR LIVER?
RIGHT. HOW SELFISH OF ME
NOT TO HAVE CONSIDERED
YOUR POSSIBLE
FUTURE NEEDS.
THEY'RE ALL DYING.
THEY'RE ALL
YOUR FRIENDS.
I'M NOT HERE
FOR AN ARGUMENT, HOUSE.
NO. RIGHT.
THAT'S ROOM 12A.
SO WHY ARE YOU HERE?
WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT I CALLED
THE MOVING VAN?
NO. THE OPERATION
IS IN TWO HOURS,
AND I'D LIKE YOU
TO BE THERE WITH ME.
NO.
WHAT--WHY?
BECAUSE IF YOU DIE,
I'M ALONE.
[A.A. Bondy'sA Slow Parade]
## ##
THANKS, JIM.
HOW YOU FEELING?
CAN'T COMPLAIN CONSIDERING
IF IT WEREN'T FOR YOU,
I'D BE DEAD--TWICE.
YOU?
I FEEL GOOD.
SENDING OUT YOUR LAUNDRY?
GOING TO REHAB.
SOME PLACE UP IN KATONAH.
UP BY YOUR NEW HOUSE,
NOT NEAR YOUR OLD HOUSE.
EASIER ON ASHLEY.
I SEE.
I WAS THRILLED TO GET
THE FAMILY BACK TOGETHER
AND MELISSA'S GREAT
IN A CRISIS,
BUT THE PERSON YOU WANT
WHEN YOU'RE DYING
ISN'T THE SAME AS THE PERSON
YOU WANT WHEN YOU'RE LIVING.
HI, JIM.
ACTUALLY, IT'S JAMES.
[groans]
YOU READY TO ADMIT THAT
HE'S A SELF-IMPORTANT JERK?
I STILL FEEL GOOD
ABOUT WHAT I DID.
YOU DON'T FEEL ANGRY?
AH. I'M A LITTLE
DISAPPOINTED.
DISAPPOINTMENT IS ANGER
FOR WIMPS.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE SO GENTLE
ABOUT EVERYTHING.
IT'S OKAY TO GET ANGRY
ONCE IN A WHILE.
YOU CAN'T CHANGE
A TABLE.
ACTUALLY, YOU CAN.
JUST NEED A COAT OF PAINT
AND THE GUTS TO USE IT.
BONNIE.
BONNIE TOLD ME
WHAT CUDDY BID.
YOU'RE GONNA OUTBID HER?
WE DO NEED A BIGGER
REFRIGERATOR.
SHE HURT MY FRIEND.
SHE SHOULD BE PUNISHED.
YOU GOT MAD.
I'M PROUD OF YOU.
CUDDY WON'T SHARE
THAT SENTIMENT.
HOW ARE YOU GOING
TO EXPLAIN IT TO HER?
I'M CHANGING OUR ADDRESS
TO A P.O. BOX.
SHE'LL FIND OUT
EVENTUALLY.
A PROBLEM DELAYED
IS A PROBLEM DENIED.
BONNIE. I'LL TAKE IT.
BABY STEPS.