We Just Arrived.
Yeah.
The Kids Okay
On Your End?
Good.
Yeah, Yeah,
He's Very Excited.
Hey, Listen,
I Gotta Go, Okay?
I'll Call You Tomorrow.
'Scuse Me.
Get Away.
Sorry About That.
Sorry.
What's Wrong With Him?
Excuse Us.
I Oughta Go Back And Kick
The Hell Outta That Guy.
She's Old Enough.
She Didn't Have To Scream
Like That.
It's Okay, Dad.
It Didn't Bother Me.
For The First Time,
None Of These People Bother Me.
I Just Think--36 More Hours.
36 More Hours.
How Do You Figure That, Kenny?
Tomorrow At This Time,
I'm Scheduled For Surgery.
It's A Ten-Hour Procedure,
Throw Two In It For Prep.
36 Until I'm Just Another
Face In The Crowd.
Ahem.
Kenny Has A Frontonasal
Encephalocele.
It's A Midline Deformity.
He's Here To Undergo
A Facial Bipartition.
And What Does That Mean?
Well,
We Have Five Surgeons,
Four Nurses.
It's Going To Require
6 Units Of Blood.
Will It Fix Him?
It'll Repair A Lot
Of The Damage Done By--
We Need A Sound Bite.
Would You Say He'll Be Ready
For The Junior Prom?
Yeah, Yeah.
That's Probably True.
No, I Mean
I Need You To Say It.
Dr. Chase.
We Got An Issue.
Heart Rate's Sky Rocketing.
He's Over 180.
He's In V-Fib.
Paddles.
Charge To 300.
Turn That Camera Off.
Is This A Reaction
To Anesthesia?
Haven't Given It Yet.
Clear.
Crank It To 360.
I Said Turn
That Damn Camera Off!
Clear.
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
HOUSE 407
-=破烂熊字幕组=-
翻译: 校对:
时间轴:abbiemcgee
A Teenage Boy
With A Cranial
Facial Deformity
Was About To Undergo
A Reconstructive Procedure
When He Had An Unexplained
Cardiac Arrest.
Good.
Good?
I Mean, Go On.
We Have The Patient
On A Pacing Wire.
It's The Only Thing
Keeping His Heart Going.
Yeah, We Know.
We're Doctors.
Right. It W-Was...
Just For Them.
Just be yourself.
Until We Are Able
To Figure Out
Exactly What Is Causing
The Heart Block,
The Reconstructive Surgery
Is On Hold, Obviously.
That's Yourself?
Fascinating Case.
I Will See You Again
After I Have Saved His Life.
Have A Warm Bath Waiting.
Are You Following Me?
Darnell Will Be
Trailing You
Throughout The Case.
Pretend We're Not Here.
If I Do That,
Won't I Bump Into You?
We'll Stay
Out Of Your Way.
That's A Joke.
See, I Became A Doctor Because
Of The Movie Patch Adams.
Uh, Listen,
Y-You Wanna Get Ahead Of Me?
Maybe Back Up,
I Don't Know, Low Down,
So I Look More Powerful?
- That's Perfect.
- Yeah?
Also My Eyes Look Better
In Rooms With Summer Colors.
You Know What?
It's Black And White--
You Think I Like
The Cameras?
You Think I Want The Whole World
Watching You Check Out My Ass
And Question My Wardrobe?
Would It Be Better
If I Checked Out Your Wardrobe
And Questioned Your Ass?
A Little Part Of Me--
There Is No Little Part
Of You.
Thought That Maybe
You Would See
What Great P.R. This Could Be
For The Hospital,
And Not Make Me Force You
To Act Like A Human Being.
You Using Force On Me
Is Intriguing.
On The Other Hand,
Cameras Make People Act.
Sometimes Like Human Beings.
Sometimes Just Weird.
Sometimes They Wear
Open-Tip Bras.
It's Cold In Here.
A Less Obvious Point
Is That I Need My Team
To Be Unafraid
Of The Metaphorical Fart.
That Production Company
Is Covering All
The Medical Costs For This Kid.
So Either You Let Them
Continue Filming,
Or The Kid Goes Home
With The Same Face.
Sorry About That.
Private.
She, Um...
Waxes Her Moustache
Once A Month And...
Sometimes Gets Some Pretty
Gnarly Ingrown Hairs.
So Did He Hire You
Flat Out,
Or Are You Competing
For One Of The Spots?
I'm Not Sure
What You Mean By That.
She's Not Competing.
She Was Hand-Picked
By House.
She's Safe, Like Foreman.
So That Takes Three Spots
Down To One.
Where's Foreman?
He's In The Bathroom.
Good. Come On.
Let's Go For A Walk.
Walks Look Good On Camera.
They Give The Illusion
Of The Story Moving Forward.
New Patient.
16-Year-Old Boy
With Second Degree
Infranodal Heart Block
Post-Arrest.
Any Reports
Of Lightheadedness Or Syncope?
It's Really Not
Lightheadedness.
Why Did You
Hire Her?
Not In Front Of The Company.
Are We Gonna Be On Tv?
I'm Making A Music Video.
Come On, A Little Faster.
More Energy.
Why Are You Glad
Foreman's Not Here?
Because He Would Object
To What I'm About To Do.
Oh...
danger!
restricted access.
no metal allowed
strong magnetic field
locked.
Hey, Buddy.
You Stay In There.
We'll Be Out Here Making Sure
He Doesn't Move Again.
God! Finally
Hear Myself Think.
Our Patient--
Why Did You Hire Her?
Because She Has
Way More Diagnostic Experience
Than The Other Swimsuit Models
I Was Considering.
Our Patient Has
A Frontonasal Encephalocele
With A Midline Cleft.
Eew.
Don't Stare
Directly At It.
So What Caused Big Head's
Heart To Stop?
Simple--His Big Head.
Increased Intracranial Pressure
Would Cause Heart Block.
Wrong, 16 Years
They've Been Testing
That Insane Noggin
To Death.
what about ???
He Has A Midline Anomaly
On His Head.
Makes Sense He'd Have A Midline
Anomaly In His Heart Too.
That 16 Years Of Testing
Didn't Show?
Why Did You
Bring Her In So Late?
It's Not Fair.
The Rest Of Us--
Hey, Hey, You Wanted Fair,
You Picked The Wrong Job.
The Wrong Profession.
The Wrong Species.
Forget The Deformity.
Treat The Patient Like He's Any
Other Really, Really Ugly Kid.
Infection
Could Be Endocarditis.
Well, Since He Doesn't Have
A Prosthetic Heart Valve,
I Assume You're Thinking
He's An Iv Drug User?
House Said Assume He's Normal.
Dealers Don't Ask For I.D. And
Don't Care What You Look Like.
Nice. You're Right
About The Habit.
You're Wrong
About The Substance.
Blackened Skin
Under The Nose
Equals Frostbite
From Huffing Freon.
Freon's Toxic.
Damages The Heart.
Discoloration Could Be
Acanthosis Nigricans.
It's A Common Side Effect
Of These Deformities.
There's Also Discoloration
On The Cheeks And Forehead.
Do A Nuclear Study.
If I'm Right, You'll See
Scarring Of The Heart.
I'm Not Part
Of Some Game, Am I?
I Gave Up A Career Because
I Thought This Was A Firm Offer.
Yes.
This Is A Real Offer.
I Think
She Might Be An Idiot.
Who?
She Can't Be An Idiot.
She Was In The Cia,
For God's Sake.
The Bay Of Pigs
Was A Daring Triumph.
She Had Good Ideas
In Langley.
All Your Ideas.
She Was Able To Identify
That They Were Good Ideas.
Stab In The Dark Here.
Is She Pretty?
She's New.
She's Nervous.
She's A "C" Cup.
She Said One Dumb Thing
In A Differential.
They All Say Dumb Things
In Differentials.
A "D" Cup?
She's No Good.
Just Fire Her.
I Can't.
I Just Hired Her.
She Left A Career.
Wow.
You Know,
That's Actual Guilt,
Or I've Got To See
This Woman.
My Son Is Not
Huffing Freon.
Mr. Arnold, Dr. House
Is Like A Savant
When It Comes
To Diagnostics.
What's His Genius
Theory?
Because Kenny's Not Normal,
He's Doing Drugs
To Deal With His Pain?
Maybe The Way
To Look At This
Is That You Are Normal.
And What's That
Supposed To Mean?
You're Like
Any Other Parent
Who Thinks His Kid
Can't Be Doing Drugs.
We're Doing This 'Cause
My Dad Thinks I'm On Drugs?
I Was Doing Drugs
Behind My Parents' Back
At Your Age, And I Had
A Lot Less Reason To Be--
Not That Your Life
Must Be Miserable.
Not That I'm Suggesting
That You Should Be Doing Drugs.
How's School Going?
I'm Homeschooled.
Really?
You're Lucky.
Going To School
Was Boring.
My Dad Took Me Out, And It
Wasn't 'Cause It Was Boring.
Well, I Had A Rough Time
In School Too.
Maybe Not Like You,
But, Uh...
You Know, I Mean, I Don't Mean
To Compare Our Situations.
Actually, I Guess I Am
Comparing Our Situations,
But Only To Show You
How Yours Is Worse.
You Can Edit That Out, Right?
So I Don't Look Like An Idiot.
Relax. Everyone Acts Like
An Idiot Around Me.
What Makes You Think
It's Not An Act?
Can I Have Something
For My Headache?
Yeah. Is That New?
16 Years Old.
Has The Same Birthday I Do.
I'm Gonna Start
The Test Now.
Study Showed No Signs
Of Scarring In Kenny's Heart.
It Wasn't Drugs.
Well, Then Give Me
Something Better?
What's Causing Heart Block?
Could Be Toxoplasmosis.
We Should Do An Lp
To Test For Infection.
If It Was Toxoplasmosis,
We Would Have Seen
Enlarged Lymphs.
And Because You're Not
Pretty Enough To Be An Idiot,
You Must Know That Already.
Which Means You Just Said It
Because You Wanna Do An Lp To
Look For Intracranial Pressure.
Because It Is
Intracranial Pressure.
Wait. I'm Not Done.
You Thought
I Wouldn't Catch On,
Which Means Either You Think
I'm An Idiot,
Which Is Flattering--
I'm Doing My Hair Differently--
The Kid's Got Headaches.
He's Been Popping
Acetaminophen Like Peanuts.
How Could You Possibly
Think That I Was Done?
I Prefaced That With An Either.
It Needs An "Or."
Or You Are An Idiot--
Which Is Possible.
I'm Not Great At Judging
Men's Looks.
The O.R.
And The Mri Room.
Yes.
Dr. House
Frequently Conducts
Differential Diagnoses
In A Variety Of Places.
He Feels That A...
Change In Venue
Often Leads To A Change
In Thinking Processes.
I Have To Go Take Care
Of Something Else.
Just Let Me Do A Ct Scan,
See If I'm Right.
The Sooner We Fix
The Problem,
The Sooner We Can Get
To His Reconstructive Surgery.
Yeah, Who Cares If You're Dead?
It's How You Look.
Well, Since You've
Given Me Nothing Better,
We're Back To Drugs.
The One Thing
We Know It's Not.
Decreased Uptake
On The Membranous Septum.
Could Be An Artifact.
We Can Redo It, But--
Nothing's Nothing.
Do An Ep Study.
Ep Study Means We Have
To Stop This Kid's Heart.
I'll Set It Up.
You Have A Minute
To Be Disemboweled?
I'm Gonna Thread
This Catheter
Through Different Areas
In Your Heart,
And Once I've Found
The Right Pathway,
I'll Apply
Some Electrical Energy.
It'll Stop My Heart?
It Sounds Worse Than It Is.
You'll Be Fine.
Is It Gonna Hurt?
There'll Be Some Discomfort.
If You've Done Drugs,
I Understand.
Being Different's
Really Hard.
Kenny, Um...
It's More Important
For You To Get Better
Than To Worry About
Getting In Trouble.
If I Did Drugs, That Could
Explain My Heart Problem?
It Could.
Then You Can Do The Surgery
To Fix My Face?
That's Why We're Here.
You Know How
Famous People...
Everywhere They Go,
People Are Watching Them,
Staring?
They Never Have A Chance
To Just Be.
You Know, And A Lot Of Them
Turn To Drugs.
People Stare At Them
Because They're Beautiful,
But Me, They Just Stare.
You Okay?
I Need To Know
What Kind Of Drugs, Kenny,
And How Much.
Um, Coke, Mostly.
A Lot Of Coke.
And Then, Uh,
When I Run Out,
I Usually Go To Lsd,
Or, Uh, Or Acid.
Those Are The Same Thing.
They Are?
You Don't Do Drugs,
Do You?
I Drink From My Dad's
Liquor Cabinet--
We're Not Gonna Do
This Test.
no.
I Need You To Turn
On Your Side.
We Need To Intubate.
and i need some help here.
Too Bad You Guys
Are Going
For A Theatrical Release.
Vomiting Blood Would Have Made
A Great Act Out.
Likely Causes.
Mallory-Weiss Tear.
No Pallor, No Melena.
Why Are You
Wearing A Tie?
Uh, I Always Wear Ties.
I'm A Doctor.
Please Don't Look
At The Camera.
Sorry.
Nasal Papilloma.
Hemorrhage Could Have
Overwhelmed The Heart.
Nice Lipstick.
Thank You.
Bad Idea.
Hahemorrge
Came After The Block.
House, Let Them
Do Their Job.
Anybody Here More Interested
In The Medicine,
A Little Less Interested
In The Paparazzi?
Upper G.I. Bleed.
Could Be Something
He Ate Or Drank.
Maybe A Peptic Ulcer.
Good.
Except No Abdominal Pain.
Patient Hasn't Lost
His Appetite,
And The Last I Checked,
The Gastrointestinal Tract
Isn't Connected
To The Heart.
Yeah. But Other Than That,
Real Good.
Nasopharyngeal Angiofibrosis.
I Just Said
It Wasn't A Nasal Tumor.
Stomach Cancer.
Tumor Causes Bleeding.
Body's Reaction To The Tumor
Causes Paraneoplastic Syndrome
Which Leads
To Heart Block.
Finally! Someone Who Is Not
Just A Pretty Face.
You And Taub Run The Scope,
find the tumor.
Uh, Could Be Dangerous.
If The Bleeding
Was Caused By Liver Failure
As The Result
Of The Intracranial Pressure--
Liver Is The One Organ
You Can't Ascribe
To Intracranial Pressure.
True.
Intracranial Pressure
Can Cause Liver Problems.
It Causes An Increase
In The Cavernous Sinus Pressure
Which Causes Pressure
In The Superior Vena Cava
Which Shuts Down The Liver.
You Just Think
Of That?
No.
Then Why Didn't You
Say Anything--
Think It Would Change His Mind?
Not A Chance.
House Would Have Undercut Me,
Ordered Me To Do A Procedure
I Just Argued Against,
And Then I'd Look Like
A Hypocrite
In Front Of The Thousands
Of People
And Potential Future Employers
Watching This Film.
If You're Right,
And We Stick A Scope Back Down
A Kid With Liver Failure,
He Could Bleed Again.
I Know.
He Just Vomited Blood.
Isn't That Dangerous?
No. You're In Good Hands.
Okay.
All Right.
Well, It's Great How He
Rebounded From That Setback.
What Setback?
He Didn't Tell You
About The...
Well, It's His Right.
Records Were Sealed.
Personally, I Think
He Was Just Tapping His Foot
And Reaching For
The Toilet Paper.
Obviously,
It Was A Witch Hunt.
Do You Think
They Singled Him Out Because...
No, Literally
A Witch Hunt.
Dr. House
Is A Practicing Wiccan.
It's A Beautiful Religion.
It's Very Caring.
Hey, Hey, Hey, Hey.
You Have An All-Access Pass
To The Case,
Not My Fave Five,
So Go.
Come On, Come On,
Let's Go.
I Think I'm Going Blind.
Hairy Palms Too?
She Said Something
Idiotic Again,
And I Didn't
Even Notice It.
Foreman Had To Point Out
That It Was Idiotic.
She's Making Me An Idiot.
That's Cute.
You Have A Crush.
No, I Think
It's Something Systemic.
Thirteen's Pretty.
You're Obviously Okay With Her.
She Killed A Patient.
The Bitch Is Pretty.
The Bitch Is A Bitch.
- Ask Her Out.
- The Bitch?
She's A Bitch.
No, The One That's
Making You An Idiot.
The Story Of Life--
Boy Meets Girl.
Boy Gets Stupid.
Boy And Girl
Live Stupidly Ever After.
Pretty Girl Kill Again?
Nope. Elephant Boy
Just Vomiting Up Blood Again.
No Tumors
In The Patient's Stomach, So--
But The Scope
Caused Variceal Bleeding.
Took 20 Minutes
Of Banding To Stop It.
Taub Was Right
About The Liver Failure.
Yeah.
His Craniofacial Deformity
- Is Causing Intracranial Pressure, just cause--
- No.
Where Are The Nose Bleeds?
Where's The Labored
Breathing?
You're Right About Me
Being Wrong.
You're Wrong
About You Being Right.
I Need New Ideas.
Anybody.
Does It Bother You
That This Kid's Gonna Die
'Cause You Won't
Put Down That Camera?
At All, You Know?
Your People Should Be
Extra Motivated.
I'm Sure They All
Wanna Look Good In The Film.
No, 'Cause Now They're
Too Worried About Looking Bad.
Dr. House, Heart Block
Plus Liver Failure
Could Mean Autoimmune.
Maybe Scleroderma.
Foreman,
Does That Make Sense?
Not Without Tight Skin
On The Hands,
Muscle Weakness,
And A 30-Year-Old Patient.
Liver Failure
Plus Heart Block Could Be
A Mitochondrial Disorder.
Hey, Say What
She Just Said.
Liver Failure Plus Heart Block
Could Be A Mitochondrial
Disorder?
Go Look For Signs
Of Retinal Degeneration.
No, It's Icp.
You're Only
Gonna See Swelling.
Take Him With You,
So He Can See
The Degeneration Too.
So Before You Worked Here
In The E.R.,
You Worked For House,
Right?
Three And A Half Years.
Why Did You Leave?
Hey, I Don't Wanna
Be On Tv.
I'm Not Signing
A Release.
We'll Blur You Out.
Take Off Your Pants.
You Gonna Be Able
To Use Any Of This
If I Start Swearing?
Did House Treat You As Badly
As He Treats
His Current Fellows?
Loaded Question.
Fawwwrk!
That's Not Even A Word.
Fork!
Very Clever.
I Learned How To Be
A Doctor From House.
Or At Least A Doctor Who Learned
How To Be A Doctor From House,
If That Makes Any Sense.
Any You Left His Team
Because
You Couldn't
Stand Him Anymore?
No, No.
I...I Love Dr. House.
That's Something
We Haven't Heard.
I Mean...
What Did You
Ask Me Again?
Why You Left.
I...I Loved Being
Around Him...
Professionally, You Know.
It Was Always...
Stimulating.
Not In An Erotic Sense
Of The Word.
Fork.
They Forked.
And Then They Spooned.
Lean Forward And Place
Your Chin On The Rest.
I Can't Reach It.
Uh, Scooch In
A Little.
I'll Take Care
Of It.
Just Like Last Time?
Maybe We Should Try This
The Old-Fashioned Way, Hmm?
Okay, Look Up To The Ceiling
And Try Not To Blink, Okay?
Okay, Good.
Now Straight Ahead.
There It Is.
Swelling.
No Degeneration.
It's Not Mitochondrial.
Swelling Proves There's
Increased Pressure In His Brain.
Absolutely.
So Now We Can Schedule
The Reconstruction.
Absolutely Not.
Your Test Proved You Wrong.
We Found Exactly
What I Predicted We'd Find.
Swelling Means
There's Increased Pressure.
You Get A Gold Star
Of David
For Proving That, Yes,
This Kid Has A Big Head,
And Big Heads
Cause Pressure.
But It Doesn't
Explain The Liver.
Too Much Acetaminophen Does.
Jra Explains All Of It,
Including The Liver.
One Theory's Better Than Two.
Treat With Steroids.
If You're Wrong,
Steroids Are Gonna Mess
With His Immune System,
Put Off His Surgery
For Months.
You Really Wanna Lose
This Argument
In Front Of The Camera?
I'll Speak
To The Father.
Dr. House Believes
That Kenny Has Jra,
Juvenile Rheumatoid
Arthritis.
We Need To Start
Administering Steroids.
Will The Steroids
Fix It?
I Don't Think
He Has Jra.
I Think Dr. House
Is Wrong
And That The Steroid Treatment
Could Be Dangerous.
I Think I Can Get House
Thrown Off The Case,
And Get Kenny
The Facial Surgery He Needs.
The Father Refused Steroids
Until We're Sure
About The Diagnosis.
I Am Sure.
It's Jra.
And Why Would He Even
Doubt That,
Unless A Former Fellow Of Mine
Was Chirping In His Ear.
The Decision Was His.
I Merely Voiced My Concern.
Why'd You Take
This Job?
He's Got A Bulging Cyst.
You Had A Perfectly Good
Plastic Surgery Practice,
Lots Of Money.
Fluids Aren't Draining
Properly.
Temptation To Come Screw
With Me
Just Too Much For You?
There's Gotta Be
A Better Reason.
He Needs Surgery
To Drain It.
Oh, And I Think I Mentioned
This Earlier--You're Fired.
What You Did
Was Over The Line.
Get Out.
But Don't Go Anywhere.
You're Not Fired.
Yet.
No One Is Firing Anyone
In The Middle Of This Case.
Not While
Those Cameras Are Here,
And Not While Taub Is The Only
Person That This Father Trusts.
Where Are You Going?
To Do What I Always Do
In These Situations--
Treat My Patient
Behind His Back.
That's One Option.
Or You Can Do A Ct Scan
Of The Kid's Head.
If There's No Midline Shift,
We Know Taub Was Wrong,
And You Get Your Consent
To Give The Kid Steroids.
Just A Warning.
We Have To Start
Getting Consent
Every Time
We Do A Procedure,
Soon They'll Be Asking
For Informed Consent.
Didn't Think You Had The Guts
To Stage A Coup.
Coup Failed.
I'm Scheduled For Execution
At Dawn.
No, You're Not.
No Reprieve
From The Governor.
You're A Test Result Away From
Becoming House's Frontrunner.
He Doesn't Care About
What You Said Or What You Did
Five Minutes Ago.
He Just Wants
The Next Good Idea.
Show Me 20% Magnification
Of The Forebrain.
I Look At Our Patient...
Soon As I Saw His Face,
I Saw A Regular Kid.
One Thing About Being
A Plastic Surgeon--
You Don't See What Is,
You See What Could Be.
You Talk Like That
Around House,
Doesn't Matter How Many
Good Ideas You Come Up With.
So...
Tell Me What You Don't
Like About Yourself.
Gosh, Uh...
There's So Many Things.
Uh, Is Dr. Taub Available?
Because He Was
Very Highly Recommended.
Well, He's No Longer
Practicing With Us,
But I've Taken Over
All His Files
So If You Tell Me
What Needs Work--
Do You Know Why He Left?
He Had Personal Issues To Deal
With, So If We Could Just--
Oh, My Goodness.
Is He Okay?
Oh, Yeah, He's Fine.
'Cause My Friend Had His Ears
Done By Dr. Taub.
Should He Worry
That They May...Pop Back?
No, It Wasn't
A Professional Issue.
I'm Sorry I Really Can't Go
Into More Detail.
Shall We Discuss
Your Needs?
You Know That Toe
Next To The Big Toe?
Mine's Bigger
Than My Big Toe.
Is There Any Way
To Shorten It?
Or Make My Big Toe Bigger,
Like A Toe-Gmentation?
Did He Lie, Cheat,
Or Steal?
You're Not Here
For A Consultation, Are You?
What Gave Me Away?
Was It My Obviously
Perfect Feet?
Hi.
Ct Shows--
Let's Go.
What Are You Two
Doing Here?
Skipping Three Scenes.
Ct's Back.
He's Gonna Say That There's
Evidence Of An Anomaly.
I'm Gonna Say He's Wrong.
He's Gonna Go Back
To The Father,
And We'll All
End Up Here.
Defect Is Pushing
On The Right Frontal Lobe.
This Bend Is A Sign
Of Herniation.
Or It's A Sign
Of Increased Pressure From Jra.
Dr. Taub Would Rather
Distract You From The Truth
With Sparkly Things
Like 4-Carat Diamonds.
House.
Your Partner Said That You Left
For Personal Reasons.
But Your Wife Said
You Lost A Patient.
Son Of A Bitch.
You Spoke To My Wife?
See, That Confused Me.
Why Would You Give Her
A Diamond
If You Screwed
Somebody Else Over?
If You Screwed Her Over,
I Mean, I Could--
Get That Camera Out Of Here.
You Say Anything
To Her?
Just Asked Questions.
Get Them
Out Of Here Too.
We're Doctors.
I Screwed Around
With A Nurse.
It Became A Deal.
My Partners Found Out,
And I Resigned.
There. Happy?
If You Could Be
A Bit More Descriptive,
I'd Be Happier.
Some People Pop
Pain Pills.
I Cheat.
We All Have Our Vices.
Taub.
I Don't See It.
Stay Away From The Family.
House, Start Steroids,
And Stay Away From His Family.
Wow. You Are Ugly.
Wow.
You're An Ass.
I Have A Deformity.
I Know. that's why
You're Ugly.
But You're A Lucky Boy.
Anywhere Else
In The Animal Kingdom,
Your Parents Would Have
Eaten You At Birth.
Your Son Needs Steroids.
Dr. Cuddy Agrees.
Does Dr. Taub?
He's...Not A Real Doctor.
He's A Plastic Surgeon.
All He Cares Is That Your Son
Looks Good In His Coffin.
So I'm Supposed
To Believe You.
The Doctor Who Cares.
You Shouldn't Care
If I Care.
I Don't Trust You.
Because I Don't Think
The Surgery's Important?
You're Putting Your Trust
In Someone
Who Does Think
The Surgery's Important.
You're Willing To Take Chances,
To Risk His Life
For Something He Doesn't Need.
I Do Need It.
I Can't Have
Real Relationships.
I Can't Even Have
A Real Conversation.
Not Even With My Dad.
Dad...
I Know You Love Me.
But You Don't
Treat Me Normal.
You're Always Protective.
The World
Can Always Go To Hell.
But You Never Yell
At Me...
Even When I Screw Up.
I Wanna Be Normal.
Take Your Steroids.
You Get To Live.
Then You Can Do
Your Surgery.
And It'll Only Change
Your Face.
It Won't Change
Who Your Face Made You.
We're Gonna Get Caught.
Not On Film.
All Their Camera
Equipment's In Here.
Where Did You Get
Those Keys?
Blue, The Janitor.
What?
That's His Name.
His Name's Lou.
Owe Him An Apology.
Just Watch
20 Minutes Of The Stuff.
Tell Me If
I'm Out Of My Mind.
Finally,
We Have Video Evidence.
Dr. House, Heart Block
Plus Liver Failure
Could Mean Autoimmune,
Maybe Scleroderma.
Foreman, Does That
Make Sense?
Not Without Tight Skin
On The Hands,
Muscle Weakness,
And A 30-Year-Old Patient.
Can I See That Again?
What Did You Miss?
She Screwed Up.
I Didn't--
No, Just The Part
Where She Leans Forward.
I Think You Can
See Through Her Dress.
Upper Gi Bleed.
Could Be From Something
He Ate Or Drank.
- Maybe A Peptic Ulcer.
- Good.
You...Thought That Was
A Good Idea?
What Am I Gonna Do?
Just Enjoy.
I'm Gonna Keep Her Around
Because She Makes Me An Idiot?
Well, You're Protected.
Foreman Seems Immune.
You Think He's Gay?
Did He Become An Idiot
Around Chase?
Nasopharyngeal
Angiofibroma.
I Just Said It's Not
A Nasal Tumor.
Wait A Minute.
Rewind That.
Was That Thirteen?
Wow.
I Can't Believe
I'm That Guy.
Every Guy Is That Guy.
I'm Not Every Guy.
What,
Is This Semantics Here?
Okay--All Guys
Are That Guy.
I'm Not All Guys.
Cameron Was Smart.
You Know, I'm...
Beginning To Doubt That.
I Wanted To Clarify
Something I Said Earlier--
"I Love Dr. House."
And Then I Qualified It,
Which, After Thinking
About It,
I Didn't Really
Need To Do.
I Did Love Being
Around Him.
I Guess I Just Wanted
To Qualify
What I Qualified Before.
I'm Looking Defensive,
Aren't I?
No, No, I Think That's Great.
Clears Everything Up.
It's No Big Deal, Really.
There's A Mass Lesion
In The Left Anterior Temporal
Lobe Surrounded By Edema.
Did You Just Insult Me
In Pig Latin?
Dr. House, Please.
Would You Just Take
A Look At This?
The Defect Is Causing
This Nodular Shadow Here.
You See It?
You're Right.
I Didn't See That Before.
Come On, Let's Go.
Hey.
I Know You Think
You're Feeling Better
On Account Of Feeling Better.
But This Trusted
Family Doctor
Thinks That He's Found
A Mass Lesion.
So If You Could
Lie Back Down
And Struggle To Breathe--
Okay.
You Were Right.
I'm Thrilled I'm Wrong.
This Is Great, Kenny.
You're Gonna Get
Your Surgery Now.
First Person
I'm Coming Back To See Is You.
'Cause Compared To Me,
You're Gonna Look Like Butt.
Hey.
What, No Comeback?
Look At That.
What?
His Little Finger.
It's Twitching.
No, It's Not.
Just Give It A Second.
- There.
- And?
He's Not Better.
What's Wrong?
My Diagnosis.
I Don't Know
What He Has.
Cancel The Surgery.
Involuntary
Muscle Movement.
A Twitching Finger
Is A Symptom?
The Body Doing Something
It's Not Supposed To Do
Is The Definition
Of A Symptom.
Kid's About To Have
A Life-Changing Operation.
He's Nervous.
Or He's Not.
Or You Were Right.
The Kid Got Better
When We Put Him On Steroids.
This Is Jra,
And It's Under Control Now.
Or The Steroids
Have Just Tempered
His Condition.
He Had A Haircut,
Still Got Bad Hair.
What About Lyme Disease?
It Explains Everything--
The Heart Issues,
Internal Bleeding,
Even Why It'd Get Better
On Steroids.
On The Other Hand,
If He Has Lyme Disease,
There Would Be
Other Subtle Clues,
Like A Huge,
Target-Shaped Rash.
But Thanks
For Playing.
Why Can't You Just
Accept The Fact
That You Cured This Kid?
You Want To Stop
His Surgery.
You're Not Normal,
So You Don't Want Anybody Else
To Be Normal.
You Don't Think
Normal's Healthy.
could be Rheumatic Fever.
Also Explains
Why The Steroids Helped.
It's A Similar
Inflammatory Disease.
Rheumatic Fever
Doesn't Explain Liver Failure.
Taub Thinks
That Acetaminophen Does.
Fine. Let's Test
Your Theory.
Remove His Pacing Wire.
If He's Better, His Heart'll
Beat Just Fine On Its Own,
And Then He Can Have
His Operation.
If I'm Right,
His Heart Will Stop.
Kutner, Have The Paddles
On Standby.
Another Chance
To Blow Someone Up.
There'll Be Some
Minor Discomfort,
And You'll Feel A Slow,
Steady Pulling Sensation.
Are You Sure His Heart
Is Ready For This?
Absolutely.
He's Convinced He's Sure.
Whereas...
I Care About Your Son
And Have, Therefore, Brought
A Professional Defibrillist.
We're Not Gonna Need Those.
Dad, I Feel Fine.
My Finger Hasn't Moved
In A While.
Okay.
Take Him Off.
Here We Go.
Heart Rate's
85 Beats Per Minute.
Bp 110 Over 70.
Is He Okay?
I Feel The Same.
He's Fine.
You're Fine.
Thank God!
What Do You Mean,
Thank God?
God's The Guy
Who Gave It To Him.
Thank You.
Can You Tell Us
About The Procedure?
We Have To Use Both An Extra
And Intracranial Approach
To Get Enough Exposure
To Reduce
The Encephalocele Cyst
And Do The Bony Reconstruction.
And How Are You Participating
In The Procedure?
She's Not.
They Don't Want Me Here,
Because They Think
The Kid's cured.
I Don't.
And What Do You Think
The Problem Is?
Wish I Knew.
I Just Know That
If Dr. House Is Right,
Something's Gonna Go Wrong.
Dr. House Doesn't
Think He's Right.
Well, Then, I'll Just Waste
A Few Hours Watching A Surgery.
The Danger Is
We Have To Reconstruct
All The Way Down
To The Cranial Base.
And There Are
Some Big Vessels Down There.
So What We'll Do Is We'll
Work Our Way Down To Here--
When Were
These Pictures Taken?
About...Three Weeks Ago.
Why? What Do You See?
The Acanthosis Nigricans
Was Already There.
It's Been There
A Lot Longer Than That.
Probably His Whole Life.
What About
Around His Hairline?
What? There's
No Discoloration.
There Is Now.
I Have A New Theory.
Their Bad Ideas Don't Indicate
A Lack Of Intelligence.
It Indicates An Open Mind,
The Willingness Not
To Be Trapped By Conventional--
You've Got A Problem.
Tell Me Something
I Don't Know.
You Hire Beautiful Girls,
Enslave Them,
Force Them
To Be Around You,
Because You Don't Know How
To Have An Actual Relationship.
If They're Qualified,
Keep Them.
If Not,
Fire Them And Ask Them Out.
You Do Realize That "Tell Me
Something I Don't Know"
Is Just An Expression.
Thirteen--
You Think That Just Because
She's As Beautiful,
- Ergo...
- No.
You Think That Because
She Hasn't Had A Decent Idea--
No, My Point Is She's
About To Enter Your Office,
So You Should Shut Up.
You Were Right
About The Diagnosis.
Yes. It Was Jra.
I'm Very Proud.
No, I Mean You Were Right
About Being Wrong.
He's Got Lyme Disease.
It Explains Everything.
Could You Just
Hold Up Some Fingers
So I Can See
If I'm Literally Blind?
We Ruled Out Lyme Disease
Hours Ago.
All The Symptoms Fit.
I Am So Ashamed.
Is She Really That Good-Looking?
Apparently.
How Many Lives Have Been Lost
Because Of Pretty Girls?
The Target Rash
Is Hiding.
No One Ever Looked At Him
Closely Enough.
She's Getting Uglier
By The Second.
We Can Try And Pretend
We're Above It.
We Can Try
And Intellectualize It Away,
But Ultimately,
Shiny, Pretty, Perky Things
Are Good,
And Ugly, Misshapen
Teenage Boys Are Repulsive.
The Question Was
Do You Resent Dr. Cuddy's
Interference In Your Practice?
Oh!
Well, Then I Guess My Answer
Wasn't Very Helpful, Was It?
Mini-Stud, Stand Up.
I Spoke To Your
Other Partner.
- After Cuddy Told You--
- No, I Stayed Away.
Did It All
Over The Phone.
I Asked For A Reference,
Said You Were Applying
For A Plastic Surgery Job.
Oh, God!
Yeah.
He Went Nuts.
Apparently,
You Signed A Non-Compete.
Now, Why Would You
Agree To That?
I Don't Wanna Practice
Plastic Surgery.
No. You Sign A Contract
Because Someone's Making You.
Someone's Getting Something
From You.
What Did They
Give You In Return?
They Agreed
To Keep Their Mouths Shut.
So You Gave Up
Your Chosen Career
Just So They'd Be Quiet?
I Love My Wife.
And You Risked This Job
With Nothing To Fall Back On?
I Thought You Were Wrong.
Sit Back Down.
You're Keeping Him
Because He's A Philanderer?
Where Do I Sign Up?
Ask The Mormon.
I'm Keeping Him
Because He's Interesting.
Dr. Terzi,
Would You Please Stand Up?
Nice.
I Have Treated You
Unfairly.
Prejudged You.
And For Me To Be
A Better Person,
I Have To Rectify
That Situation.
You're Fired.
You Wanna...
Grab Some Dinner?
Maybe A Movie?
Seriously.
Just Days Ago, With Kenny's
Condition Worsening,
It Was Dr. Gregory House
Reassuring Kenny And His Father.
I Care About Your Son.
The Charming House,
Who Happens To Be A Film Buff
With A Soft Spot
In His Heart For Children,
Told Us
How He Got His Start.
See, I Became A Doctor Because
Of The Movie Patch Adams.
Determined To Save
The Boy's Life as well as...
The Horror...
Well, It's Nice Of Them
To Send Us An Early Copy.
Not So Much Sent As Stolen.
In The End,
It Was Dr. Gregory House
Who Served As Not Only A Doctor,
But A Rock
For Kenny And His Father.
You're Putting Your Trust
In Someone
Who Does Think
The Surgery's Important.
House, One Of Those
Rare Doctors---
God--
Wears His Heart
On His Sleeve
I Was Saying That Was
A Stupid Thing To Do.
It's Difficult
Not To Be Moved.
Oh, Stop It.
Suddenly I Don't Feel Like
I Can Trust
Michael Moore Movies.
Where Are You Going?
Kittens
To Get Out Of Trees?
Deaf Kids
To Read To?
I Owe It To The World
To Make Sure This Evil
Never Sees The Light Of Day.
Is there Anything Else, Kenny?
Thank You, Dr. House.
Thank You.
破烂熊字幕组
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
欢迎加入
www.tvsubtitles.net