Bring It Up
About Six More Feet.
Okay, You Can Go Ahead
And Start Dropping It.
Whoa.
Whoa!
Rico!
Class Is Over.
What's Going On?
Who Are You?
I'm A Doctor.
Did You Have A Corneal
Transplant Five Years Ago?
Yes.
Every Other Patient Who Had
A Transplanted Organ
From That Donor
Is Either Dead Or Dying.
You Got A Purse?
I Feel Fine.
I Don't Mean To Scare You,
But So Did The Others.
破烂熊字幕组作品 - =http:/Www.
Ragbear. Com=- 豪 斯 医 生 第五季 第2集
- =破烂熊字幕组=-
翻译：个人ID 校对：个人ID 时间轴：卢 斌
One Living, One Almost Dead.
Four Fully Dead.
Nothing In Common
Except Their Donor.
Carl Got A New Heart
And Lung.
Liver Kills Him.
Tibalt Got A New Liver,
Lung Killed Him.
Holly Got A New Kidney,
Her Heart Blows Up.
And Frank, The Old Guy
Gasping For Breath Upstairs,
He Got An Intestinal Graft,
His Pancreas Is Failing.
All Within Eight Months
Of Each Other.
And In Each Case, Serious
Complications Came On Suddenly
And Without Warning.
Which Means Arrhythmia,
Massive Pulmonary Embolus,
Or Cerebral Bleed.
What Did Wilson Do
For Me?
If The Donor Had
An Infection That Somehow
Slipped By A Screening,
It Could Lay Dormant-
Five Organ Systems Hit.
Would Need Five Infections
For It To Somehow Slip
By Screening.
Oh, Sure, He Made Me Laugh
On A Rainy Day,
Made Me See The Colors
I Never Knew-
None Of The Donated Organs
Were Hit.
It Means Whatever They Got
Came From The Donor's Blood.
That Wouldn't Help Us Narrow
Down What-
It Narrows Down Who.
Corneal Transplants
Are Bloodless.
It Means
Apple's Gonna Be Fine.
You Secure Enough
In That Theory To Send Her Home?
I Guess We Could Wait
Till We Figure Out
What's Wrong With Frank.
On The Other Hand,
Gilbert Gottfried
Makes Me Laugh.
And How Many Colors
Are There Really?
Once You Got Red, Blue,
And Green-
He Paid For Your Lunch,
Liked Monster Trucks,
And Was Your Conscience.
Autoimmune Disease.
A.N.A. At Autopsy
Of All Four Victims Were Normal.
Wouldn't Cover Vasculitis.
Henoch-Schonlein Purpura-
Antiphospholipid Antibodies,
Normal.
Then That Leaves Cancer.
Cancers Have Names.
They Have A Progression.
They Affect
Specific Organs.
Bone Cancer Can't Turn
Into Liver Cancer.
Forget Cancer.
It's Cancer.
It's Not Cancer.
You're Right,
Of Course.
What Was I Thinking?
No Single Type Of Cancer
Blew Up Three Organs
In The Chest
While Also Herniating
In The Fighter's Brain Stem.
The Fighter's Irrelevant.
You Don't Like Coincidences.
It Would Be A Coincidence
If Six Transplant Recipients
Had Nothing Else Wrong
With Them-
Like Being An Idiot,
Which Leads To Getting
Your Head Knocked Off.
The Others Had Cancer.
Four Autopsies
And About 1,000 Lab Tests Say
It's Not Cancer.
Redo The Thousand Tests
And The Four Autopsies.
Taub And Kutner,
Check Out The Donor.
Find Out Which Cancer-
He Didn't Die Of Cancer.
His Head Got Chopped Off
In An Industrial Accident.
Find Out Which Cancer
Would Have Killed Him.
Check The Home And Office
For Carcinogens, Toxins-
He's Been Dead
For Four Years.
I Assume His Home's Been Rented
To Someone Else By Now.
Find Out Which Cancer
Killed Them.
Did I Forget You?
You Can Check Out
The Patient's Eye.
Put This On Dr. O'shea.
And Some Chips.
Forget Your Wallet,
House?
No.
I'll Take Care Of It.
Check.
Are You Following Me?
Word Is You're
Into Monster Trucks.
My Kids Like It.
But Not You?
Predator's Okay,
But I Think The California
Crusher Is Overrated.
Are You Checking Me Out?
You're Astute.
No. How Many Pills Did You Just Take?
Vicodin, Opioids,
Some B12.
Need A Little Kick
In The Afternoon.
You Got A Problem
With That?
I Think
I'm Falling In Love.
Her Right Eye's Failing.
No, It's Not.
Everyone Else's
Transplanted Organs Were Fine.
It Means Her Eye
Is Fine.
We Need To Remove
The Eye.
It's Her Only Working Eye.
We Could Remove The Other One,
But Since It's Not Killing Her,
I Thought This Way
Was Less Insane.
Do You Have
Some Ethical Problem
With What I'm Doing
That You Could Express
In A Unique Way
Which Might Actually Make Me
Think That I'm Wrong
Even Though I'll Never Admit It?
Yes.
You Are Funny.
The Problem's Not In Her Eye.
It's In Her Head.
You Wanna Come Over
And Watch Prescription Passion
At My Place Tonight?
You Know
I'm Not Gay, Right?
Neither Am I.
If You Don't Want To Have Sex,
That's Cool With Me.
I'm Not Coming Over
To Your Home.
I'll Grow On You.
L... P... E...
Do I Have To Be
In The Same Room As Him?
Whatever He's Got,
You've Got.
Fifth Line.
Are You Sure?
Pretty Sure.
Fifth Line.
Am I Gonna Die?
Can We Talk About Something
Besides You For A Moment?
Like Maybe The Fifth Line?
F... E... O... S... P.
Damn.
I'm Sorry.
We Need To Remove
Your Eye.
My Eye?
A Moment Ago,
You Thought You Were Dying.
Blind's Actually Good News.
Unfortunately,
He's Wrong.
You Just Did The Test.
She Didn't Squint.
Which Means The Eye Thinks
It's Fine.
It Was Wrong. I Know.
The Eye Doesn't Think.
The Brain Thinks, Which Means
If The Thinking's Wrong,
The Brain's Wrong.
Which Means It's Spread
To The Brain,
Which Means It's Too Late
For Us To Remove The Eye.
Which Means We're Gonna Have
To Remove Your Whole Head.
Don't Worry.
It Doesn't Hurt.
&&&
???
500 Different Things
Can Cause Hallucination.
Doesn't Mean
It's Neurological.
It Does If One Of
The Other Organ Recipients
Also Had A Brain Issue.
Did He Just Drop
Had Brain Issues. Hands?Them
If His Pupils Dilated,
If His Pupils Were Fixed,
If There Was A Twitch...
He Got Hit In The Head,
He Died,
No Mystery.
That Was Your Point.
Yesterday.
You Live,
You Learn.
Who Shot This?
Guy Who Runs The Gym
Has A Camera.
Uploads The Nasty Stuff
Online.
Can't See
The Dead Guy's Face.
I Can't See His Face,
Can't See The Twitch,
Can't See The Pupils-
We Know The Tennis Player
Had A Heart Problem.
We Can Maybe Tie That
To The Tuba Player's Lungs,
And Then Somehow Tie
Both Those Things,
To The Construction Worker's
Liver,
And Then Possibly Meander
Over To Frank's
Pancreatic Failure,
But Nothing Causes Simultaneous
Brain And Heart Problems.
Cancer Made No Sense.
The Head And Heart
Make Less Than No Sense.
That Makes No Sense.
Um.
I Know.
I Was Making
A Point.
Oh, Good.
I Thought You Were An Idiot.
Why Are You Talking?
Oh, The Guy Doing Manual Labor
Can't Have An Opinion?
I Might Be A Genius
Who Just Happens To Have
A Passion
For Fixing Coffee Machines.
No, I'm Obviously Not,
But That's Rude
To Make Assumptions
About People.
Donor's History Came Up Clean.
Did He Just Laugh?
No, No, I Sneezed.
He's A Genius Coffee Repairman.
Coffee Repairman
Who Wears Argyle Socks?
I Thought I Already Talked
About Not Judging.
What Kind Of Idiot
Wears Argyle Socks
With Construction Boots?
Uh, I'm Not An Idiot.
I'm Just-I'm Not Good
At Disguises.
Who Is He?
He's Apparently A Very Bad
Private Investigator.
Uh, Why Is He Pretending
To Fix The Coffee Machine?
Because I Wanted To Find Out
What You Guys Found Out
Before I Find Out
What He Found Out.
So I Can Find Out If I Need
A Private Investigator.
So, Nu?
There's No History
Of Unusual Infections,
No International Travel
In The 12 Months-
No, Seriously,
That's How I Sneeze.
He Was In Madrid
And The Bahamas.
Credit Card Receipts
Showed No-
Girlfriend Paid.
There Is No Girlfriend.
She Was
His High School Sweetheart.
High School Sweetheart
Is Married To His Best Friend.
I Know.
Shh.
She Had A Kid Four Years Ago.
Timing Fits.
She's Still Pretty Hot
Though.
You Find Out Anything
Medical?
The Kid Has A Tummy Ache.
Also, The Dead Guy Was Exposed
To Mercury, Mold,
And Hydrous Perchloric Acid
Because Their Sex Pad
Was Next To A Garage
That Was Demolished
After Those Toxins Were Found.
Oh, Yeah,
That Will Be
$2,300.
I'll Get You
A Check.
No, I Don't Take Checks.
You Think
I'm Gonna Stop Payment?
Aren't You?
Of Course, I Am.
$2,300.
That's Insane.
Actually, That Price Includes
Footage Of The Boxing Match
From Four Different Angles.
30% Of The Crowd
Paid By Credit Card.
I Got Their Names.
Four Of Them Had
Digital Cameras,
Which I Composited
Like Nasa Did
For The Pics Of Mars.
You Know, The Rovers
And All That.
Pupils Were Dilated.
But He Didn't Drop His Hands,
Which Means He Maintained
Muscle Tensity-
Say It.
You Were Right.
God, That Was Petty
Of Me.
He Maintained Muscle Tensity,
But Was Momentarily Distracted
When He Got Hit.
That's A Temporal Lobe Seizure.
Does That P.I. Guy Mean
We Don't Have To Break
Into People's Homes Anymore?
It's The Whole Reason
You Went To Medical School.
I'm Not Gonna Take That
Away From You.
He's Better
Than We Are.
And Costs More.
Gonna Biopsy The Brain.
No.
Say It.
You Were Right,
But No.
Temporal Lobe
Controls Speech,
Hearing, Memory.
She Loses Those Things,
She's Gonna Be
A Terrific Date,
But Beyond That-
We Cut Out A Piece Of It,
Good Chance She's A Vegetable.
Nothing To Hear,
Nothing To Say,
Nothing To Look Back On.
You're Right.
She Has So Much
To Live For.
Do We Have Another Patient
Who's Almost Finished
With All Their Living?
So It's Okay To Stab His Brain
Because He's Old?
No, It's Okay To Stab
His Brain
Because He's Dead
If You Don't.
Get The Widow
To Say Yes.
No.
The Lung Inflammation Is
A Complication
Of The Pancreatic Failure,
Which Is Reversible.
This Is Actually
His Best Chance.
If We Can Find Out
What's Wrong...
How Can A Test
That Will Probably Kill Him-
I Didn't Say-
You Said
It Was Extremely Risky.
What Does Extremely Mean?
Please.
I'm Sorry.
I Can't.
I Have A Husband.
I Have A Two-Year-Old
Daughter.
Her Name Is Julia.
You'd Be Saving
Her Mother.
I Think You're Lying.
You Haven't Had One Visitor.
Not One Phone Call
Since You've Been Here.
Does She Have A Child?
No.
But Her Life
Is Still Worth-
More Than My Husband's?
I Lied To Save My Life.
Wouldn't You?
Not At Another Human Being's
Expense.
No, You'd Just Rob Me
Of My Only Chance
So Your Husband Can Struggle
To Breathe
For A Few More Days.
Just Shut Up.
I Don't Want To Hear From You. Ladies.
You Want To Hate Me So You
Won't Feel Guilty. Shut Up!
Frank?
Give Me A Scalpel.
Frank.
Charge.
He's Coding.
Clear.
Frank!
Did You Get
The Consent?
No.
Tell Foreman To Get It.
Old People Are Scared
Of Black People.
It Won't Matter.
Patient's Dead.
Sa The Brain.
Don't Need Consent
For An Autopsy.
Well, At Best, We're Gonna Bat
One For Six On This One.
Thin Slices
Through The Parietal
And Temporal Lobes
Were Clean.
Occipital And
Frontotemporal Regions
Were Also-
Brain's Clean.
Moving On.
To Where?
We've Gone From Making No Sense,
To Making Less Sense,
And Then Taken
A Step Backwards.
Each Of These People
Were Killed By One Thing
That Attacked One Organ.
But Never The Same Organ.
Could The Donor Have Had
Two Things Wrong?
Or Six Things Wrong?
Metabolic Diseases Specialize.
Everything Else Specializes,
But Cancer Plays
The Field.
You're Back To Cancer?
Metastasis Is Just A Fancy Word
For Screws Around.
Any Type Of Cancer?
I Don't Know.
There Would Be Evidence
Of Cancer.
There Is.
We Just Haven't Found It Yet.
You Need It To Be Cancer
So You Have An Excuse
To Talk To Wilson.
Give Me Something Else
That Explains This Constellation
Of Patients,
Then You Can Call Me
An Ass.
I Didn't Call You An Ass.
Perforated Intestine.
If This Thing Started
As Normal Bacteria
Living In The Intestines
But Got Into A Blood Vessel
Through A Vascular Anomaly
In The Bowel Wall,
Then They Would Affect Every
Organ Through The Blood Stream.
It Screws Up Everything.
For Everyone.
Okay.
It's A Long Shot,
It Is Possible I'm An Ass.
Ironically, We Need To Do
A Colonoscopy To Confirm.
We Checked Apple Inside And Out
When She Came In;
She's Clean.
The Anomaly Would Have To Be
Intermittent
Or They All Would Have Died
Within A Day.
She Starts Getting
Abdominal Pain,
Shove A Tube Up Her Rear
Before It Can Get Away.
And Test Anyone Else
With Stomach Pain.
Everyone Else Is Dead.
Not Everyone.
The One Thing The Donor Gave
To Each Of These People
Is His Dna.
Anyone Else
Have His Dna?
You Want To Do A Colonoscopy
On A Healthy Four-Year-Old?
She Has A Tummy Ache.
If Kutner's Right,
It's Not A Tummy Ache,
It's A Fatal Brain Or Heart Or
Lung Or Liver Or Pancreas Ache.
I'm Not Gonna Scare The Hell
Out Of The Poor Kid's Mom
Because Of A Long Shot Corollary
To A Long Shot Theory.
Fine
Tell Her The Truth.
Then Ask If Daddy Knows
Who The Real Daddy Is.
Does She Have To Be Awake?
We Need Her To Tell Us
When It Hurts.
She'll Get Over It.
Your Husband Might Not Have.
What If A Kid Wants
Ice Cream?
The Sign Outside
Says 'Closed. '
Dr. O'shea's Not Right
For You.
What'd You Find Out?
Why Are You
Investigating Him?
'Cause I Need To Know
If He Lends Money Interest-Free.
What Did You Find Out?
I Want Some Ice Cream.
Not Until You Learn
To Read.
You're Supposed
To Trust Friends.
I Don't Know The Guy.
I Got No Logical Reason-
To Be His Friend?
Have You Never Seen
An After-School Special?
That Is Part Of The Pleasure
Of Friendship:
Trusting
Without Absolute Evidence
And Then Being Rewarded
For That Trust.
You're Taking Pictures
Of A Guy
Who's Having An Affair
With His Own Sister.
And You're Lecturing Me
About The Rewards Of Trust.
There Are Two Types Of People
That Hire Me.
No, Actually,
There Are Three Types
Of People That Hire Me,
But The Third Type's Irrelevant
To The Point I Want To Make.
Do You Have A Special Rate Plan
For Being A Pain In The Ass?
One Type Wants To Find Out
That They're Right,
That They're Wrong.
Which Type Am I?
You're The Third Type.
You Lead
With The Irrelevant Types?
You're The Type That Doesn't
Care If You're Right Or Wrong
Because They've Hired Me
To Investigate The Wrong Person.
That's An Actual Type?
You Want Me
To Check Out Wilson.
You Want To Find Out
If He's-
How Do You Know About Wilson?
What Do I Do For A Living?
Have You Been Checking Me Out?
I've Been Paying For That?
So Far,
You Haven't Paid For Anything.
You Want To Find Out
He's Pining;
If There's Something
About Him
That Will Tell You
He's Gonna Come Back
Or Something You Can Use
To Make Him Come Back.
Is There?
No, No, There's Nothing.
Sorry.
That Will Be $900.
I Gotta Go.
I'll Get You A Check.
Colonoscopy Was Clean.
Then That Just Leaves Cancer.
The Fact That The Kid's
Colonoscopy Was Negative
Doesn't Prove Anything.
Yes, The Fact
That It Didn't Prove Anything
Didn't Prove Anything.
Excellent Point.
We Don't Know
If The Kid Inherited Anything.
Even If She Did,
Kutner's Theory Is That
The Thing's Intermittent.
The Opening Would Have
To Be Open Shortly Before Death.
Unfortunately, We Can't Know
When Shortly Before Death Is
Until Shortly After Death.
And That Seems
Like An Obstacle.
What If There Was A Way
Around That?
Then We're Kind Of All Sweating
Over Nothing.
Not Around Death,
Around Death As An Obstacle.
We Need To See His Colon
At Work.
You Do Know
What Death Means, Right?
Without A Living System,
There's Not Enough Pressure
To Get Fluid All The Way Up.
Life We Can't Create, Yet,
But Pressure's Easy.
We Use The Same High Pressure
Water Jet
We Use To Test
Cardiac Workload.
I Mean, He's Not Gonna Be Awake
To Tell Us Where It Hurts-
It's Not Gonna-
Do It.
It's Kinda Stuck.
It's More Than Stuck.
The Bowel's Been Dead
For Six Hours.
No Matter What
You Shoot Up There, It's Closed.
This Is Nuts.
It's Adjustable.
It's Working.
Yeah. Wow.
Not Much.
Increase The Pressure.
The Endoscope's Bowing.
Push On The Stomach.
Those Are Normal
Bodily Fluids.
Yeah, Normal Bodily Sewage.
Put The Pressure
Back On.
That's The End.
No Leaks.
Wait.
What's That?
That's Just Dark
'Cause I'm At The End.
What If You're Not
At The End?
What If It's A Core Lesion?
Maybe A Little More Pressure?
Not Too Much.
If It Is The End And We-
It's Finally Accelerating.
Apple's Heart Rate
Has Become Irregular.
Breathing Is Labored.
Colonoscopy's Still Showing
No Leaks.
What If It Is Autoimmune?
What If We Don't Have
Conversations We've Already Had?
Four Out Of The Five
Didn't Linger.
They Got Sick
And Died.
We Don't Have Time To Dismiss
Things We've Already Dismissed.
Nothing Fits.
See, That's An Example
Of A Conversation
We've Already Had.
She's Sick.
Something Fits.
Ms?
No!
Okay, From Now On,
No One Says Anything
Unless No One's Said It
Before.
Where Are You Going?
You Guys Start
Immuno-Gels
On Her Csf To Look
For Hidden Protein Markers.
Then Start Sequencing
Her Genes.
I'm Gonna Start Treatment.
Treatment For What?
Cancer.
It's Not Cancer.
Chemo's Toxic.
It's Something.
Which Means We Should Treat Her
For Something.
She's Fine.
Where's Her Chart?
You Rang Emergency
To Get Her Chart?
I Know.
That Was Bad Of Me.
But I'm Pretty Sure
The Chart's Supposed To Be
Attached To The Bed
So That Gimp Doctors
Don't Have To Look
All Over The Place
While Patients Die.
Thank You So Much.
And Some Peppermint Tea
When You Get A Chance.
I Need You
To Sign Something.
Consent
To Chemotherapy.
You Found Cancer?
No.
Then You Have Tests
Indicating-
Nope.
Then Why Should I Sign It?
That's A Good Question.
It Deserves
A Complicated Answer.
Placebo Effect.
People Have Confidence
In Doctors,
They Have Confidence
In Diagnoses,
Confidence In Medicine.
Sometimes They Get
A Little Better
Just Because They Think
They Will.
And That Can Make Us Think
That The Wrong Answer
Is The Right Answer.
Which Is Very Bad.
So You Do Have Proof
That It's Cancer
But You Can't Tell Me
Because It Might Affect
The Way I React
To The Medicine?
If That Were True, And It Would
Certainly Make Sense,
Do You Think I Could Tell You
That It's True?
I Was Practically Blind
Before The Transplant.
2200 Vision.
Didn't You Cover All This
Personal Stuff With Dr. Foreman?
You Don't Care
Who I Used To Be?
You're A Post-Corneal Transplant
Math Teacher.
I Deduced That You Were
A Blind Math Teacher.
I Was An Architect.
You Gave Up Architecture
After You Could See?
The World Was Ugly.
You Think The World Would Be
Any Different
If Your Leg Was Fine?
No.
Think You'd Be Any Different
If Your Leg Was Fine?
I Mean, The Doctors Told Me
That My Life Was Gonna Be
So Much Better
Once I Could See.
I Would Date,
I Would Dance,
But, Uh, The Guys
I Hated Dancing With Before
I Hate Dancing With After.
My Parents Were Still Dead.
I Was Still Alone.
You're Fun.
You Don't Seem
All That Different.
I Haven't Given Up.
Wilson's Got A New Job,
Hasn't Started Yet, But-
So Who Are We Following?
See That Lady Up There?
You Point At The Target?
No, I'm Following The One
Halfway In Between That Point
And That Point.
Oh.
Pretty.
Who Hired You?
No One.
I Just Like Her.
You're Stalking Her?
No, No, I Followed Her Out
Of That Bookstore Back There.
You Are Stalking Her,
Just Not For Very Long.
So What Else Can You Tell Me
That I Might Care About?
He Attends This Grief Counseling
Thing Twice A Week
Where They Go Around
The Room
And Cry About Who's Dead.
Cameron's Been To His House
Several Times,
They Just Talk About Death
And Losing Loved Ones.
What-
What Are You-
If She Turns Her Head,
She's Gonna See That We're
Walking The Wrong Direction.
No, No, No,
She Won't.
I'm Very Nondescript.
Well, I'm Not.
Well, Then You Stay
Four Feet Behind Me.
How Do You Know
What They're Talking About?
I'm In The Same
Grief Counseling Group.
I Recently Lost
My Mother.
You'd Get Laid More Often
If You Told Them
You Lost A Kid.
I Didn't Lose A Kid.
You're A P.I.
Who Can't Lie?
I Can Lie.
I'm Just Not All That Good
At It.
Well, Dr. Cuddy's Been Over
To Wilson's Twice
And Phoned
A Bunch Of Times.
Foreman Called Him.
And The Rest Of The Time
Wilson's Been Reading
Meditation Books And Magazines
About Restoring Barns.
Are You Following Me?
No.
Are You Lying?
Yes.
?Commit.
It's Making Me
Uncomfortable.
Sorry.
You're Very Pretty.
More Uncomfortable.
She's Not Your Type.
Your Type Is Much Stupider
Than Her.
What Did Wilson Say
About Me?
Oh, You've Never Come Up.
In The Grief Counseling
Or In The Other-
Anywhere,
I Got Three Bugs In His Home
And One In His Car.
If I Didn't Know You,
I Wouldn't Even Know
You Existed.
Which Is Good News.
Only Two Things You Ignore-
Things That Aren't Important
And Things You Wish
Weren't Important.
And Wishing Never Works.
She's Better.
I Can Tell At Once.
Vomiting's A Side Effect
Of The Chemo.
Her Heart Rate's Stabilized,
Breathing's Good.
Amylase And Triglycerides
Are Both Coming Down.
I Guess It's Working.
Can't Believe It.
It's Cancer.
It's Not Cancer.
Labs Show That Our Patient
Is Healthier.
She's Gonna Get Sicker.
Then She's Gonna Die.
I Brought Thal Food.
What Did You See In Her?
Nothing.
It's Not Cancer.
All The Tests Say
They've Always Said
It's Not Cancer.
Treatment Proves
It's Cancer.
Eh, Treatment Proves
It Could Be Cancer.
It's Not Cancer.
This Was Your Diagnosis.
I Never Thought
It Was Cancer.
You Treated
For Cancer.
I Thought That What She Had
Acted Like Cancer.
If It Acts Like Cancer,
Maybe It'll Respond Like Cancer.
It Did.
'Cause It's Cancer.
We Have To Find Something
That Walks Like Cancer,
Talks Like Cancer,
Tastes Like Cancer,
But Isn't Cancer.
No, We Don't.
Better Is Better.
Who Cares Why?
I Do.
And So Does Tetrault.
Who?
The Dead Tuba Player.
Tibalt.
The Point Is,
He Died Last,
But He Died.
Which Means
She's Gonna Die Too.
Tibalt Wasn't Receiving
Cancer Medication.
There's A Cancer Drug
That's Used Off-Label
For Arthritis.
There's No Record
Of Arthritis.
Did You Interview
All The Tuba Students?
If He Had Joint Pain
In His Hands,
He Couldn't Have Played.
Then It Wasn't In His Hands.
Then Why Do We Care
About His Students?
One Of Them Is Canadian.
Brought Him Methotrexate
So He Could Hide His Arthritis.
Already Couldn't Afford
His Insurance.
And That Little Piece
Of Business Cost Me $700.
I'm Gonna Pass It On To The
Patient With A Steep Mark-Up.
This Makes No Sense.
I Know.
She's Dead Unless We Can Find
What's Cancer...
But Not Cancer.
Something's Missing.
I Need An Epiphany.
What Are You Billing
Out At?
$300 An Hour?
Here's Four.
There Are Other Oncologists.
Better Oncologists.
But I Need You.
Let Me Describe
The Symptoms,
Problems, Issues,
And Say Whatever
You Feel Like Saying,
Until Something Triggers
An Idea In My Head.
That's Not The Way
It Works.
You Have A Way
Of Thinking About Things.
It's Sloppy,
It's Undisciplined,
It's Not Very Linear.
It Complements Mine.
It Drives Me Down Avenues
That I Wouldn't Otherwise-
House, Please Go Away.
Cancer, But Not Cancer.
Responds To Cancer Treatment,
But There's No-
How Are You?
Don't Do This.
Please.
I'm Trying To Move On.
By Hanging Out
With Cameron,
Talking To Cuddy,
Foreman,
But Not Me.
I Paid A Private Investigator
To Spy On You.
You Didn't.
You Want To Move On From Me,
You Got To Deal With Me,
Talk To Me.
You Had No Right-
We're Not Friends Anymore.
There's No Trust
To Be Breached.
I Can Have You Followed,
I Can Call You Names,
Tell Your Secrets.
Foreman Did A Ct.
Temporal And Frontoparietal
Regions Are Normal.
Occipital Lobe, Normal.
I Have The Right
To Walk Away From You, House.
There's A World Beyond You.
You Need To Realize That,
And Even If You Don't,
I'm Moving On.
The Next Time You Knock,
I'm Not Answering.
Nothing Yet.
Keep Talking.
I'm Sorry.
You Charge Me For Listening In
On My Own Conversations?
Ha.
Yeah, Why Wouldn't I?
How Many Friends
Do You Have?
17.
Seriously?
You Have A List?
No, I Knew This Conversation
Was Really About You,
So I Just Gave You
An Answer
So You Could Get Back
To Your Train Of Thought.
Well Done.
I Have One.
Had One.
You Know,
Friends Are Important.
You're Gonna Miss-
Shut Up.
Friends Allow You To Not Sit
In A Room By Yourself.
Are You Charging Me
For This?
Are We Friends?
No.
Then Yes.
Do You Wanna Be
My Friend?
No.
You Scare Me A Little.
He Thinks If He's Not A Friend,
He Can't Talk To Me.
We Can Talk, We Can Be
Two Human Beings Talking-
I'm With Him.
Sorry.
Didn't Mean To Interrupt.
Yes, You Did.
I Was In The Middle
Of A Sentence.
Yes, I Did.
You're Repeating Yourself.
I'm Grateful.
Make Your Point.
It's Like That
"Cancer, But Not Cancer" Thing
You Were Talking About
Before.
Friends Are Friends,
Customers Are Customers,
And Everything Else
Is Everything Else.
If It's Not,
Nothing's Nothing.
And Anything Can Be Anything.
10:10. Stop The Clock.
What?
The World Is Not As Ugly
As She Thinks It Is.
Cancer, But Not Cancer.
Doesn't Make Any Sense
Unless...
Brain, But Not Brain.
Occipital Lobe's Normal.
But Her Eyes Suck.
That Lobe Should Be
Compensating.
Since It's Not, That Tells Me
That Something's In There
That Shouldn't Be In There.
Brain, But Not Brain.
Why Are You
In My Office?
To Find The Anomaly,
I Need To Chop Off
The Top Of Her Head.
Pretty Sure I Need
Your Approval For That.
I'm Gonna Trust
Your First Instinct.
I'm Not Usually Confused
When You Say Things Like That.
I'm Ordering Her Cancer
Treatment To Be Continued.
Why Does It Cost $2,300
To Fix A Coffee Machine?
Cancer Stem Cells
Are Real.
They Explain Everything.
They're Like Embryonic
Stem Cells.
They Become Whatever
They Want.
Donor Had Them,
The Recipients Got Them.
They Floated Around,
They Landed On An Organ,
Got Bathed In Cytomes
And Partially Differentiated.
And The Key Word There
Is Partially.
In The Tuba Player,
They Became Lung, But Not Lung.
In The Tennis Player, They
Became Heart, But Not Heart.
Stop Me If You've Figured Out
The Pattern.
They Looked As If They Belonged,
But They Weren't Doing
Their Jobs.
And When They Were
Really Needed,
Boom.
Chemo Worked Because Cells
Are Basically Tumors.
Chemo Shrunk Them.
You're Still Gonna Say No,
Aren't You?
You've No Proof.
I Have The Brain Scan.
The Normal Brain Scan.
This Is Why
I Need To Take Off Her Head.
Treat Or To Prove
You're Right?
To Treat.
Chemo's Not Killing
Anything.
It's Just Hiding
The Real Problem.
She's Gonna Crash.
If We Wait
Until She Does Crash,
It Might Be Too Late.
So The Next Step Is What?
I Say No, And Then
You Do Something
To Make Her Crash
So That I'll Think
You've Proven Your Theory?
I Would Never Do That.
No, You Won't.
* To Change The World *
* Start With One Step *
* However Small *
* The First Step
Is Hardest Of All *
* Once You Get Your Gait *
* You'll Be Walking Tall *
* You Said You Never Did *
* 'Cause You Might Die Tryin' *
* 'Cause You *
* If You Close Your Eyes *
* Because The House Is On Fire *
* And Think You Couldn't Move *
* Until The Fire Dies *
* The Things You Never Did *
She's Crashing!
* 'Cause You Might Die Tryin' *
* 'Cause You Might
Die Tryin' * *
You Might Want To Check
Her Iv.
From Here, It Looks Like Saline
Instead Of Chemo.
Yeah, They Look Identical.
Still.
You Should Probably Check.
You Switched
Her Meds?
How Could I?
I Had No Access.
Close Her Back Up.
Do The Surgery.
There's No Reason To-
No Reason Not To.
The Stupidly Dangerous Part
Is Already Over With.
We're Ready
With The Neural Net.
Is That Someone's Brain?
Except For The Part
That Isn't Brain.
Hey, That's The Patient I-
You Said
She'd Be Fine.
I'm A Better Liar
Than You Are.
I Swapped Her Meds.
I Mean, She's Got
A Brain Problem.
I Coulda Killed Her.
Yup.
The Neural Net Will Show Us
How Fast
Her Neurons Are Firing.
If There's Something
In The Way,
Say...
Brain That's Not Brain,
The Normal Neural Impulses
Will Be Sucked
Into A Vortex
Because They're Not Able
To Do Their Job.
The Computer
Will Then Process It
And Give Us A Picture
Of Where To Cut.
Cool.
Excuse Me?
Sorry, I Thought
That's What You Wanted To Hear.
You Think All This
Is Amazingly Cool.
And You Have No One Else, So
You're Paying A Guy To Listen.
Sorry-Just Trying To Save You
Some Cash.
I'm On The Clock.
Yeah, Why Wouldn't You Be?
You Think
This Is Interesting To Me?
House?
I See It.
Can You Get It?
I Think So.
Turns Out
You Didn't Kill Her.
Cool.
You Owe Me $5,000.
Why Are You Just Standing There,
Dr. House?
How'd You Know
Who It Is?
I Can Smell You.
Yeah, Like You're
A Field Of Roses.
Peppermint Tea.
You Ever Hear
Of The Boy Who Cried Wolf?
Never Really Bought That.
I Don't Care
How Often A Kid Cries,
He's Being Eaten By A Wolf,
Mom's Gonna Come Running.
The World Is Ugly.
People Kill.
They Go Hungry.
Just Proving A Point.
People Are Asses.
Why Are You Telling Me
This Stuff?
Because The World
Is Not As Ugly
As You Think It Is.
Your Transplanted Cornea's Fine,
Your Eye Is Fine,
But Your Brain
Wasn't Working Right.
I'm Gonna Take
The Gauze Off Your Eyes Now.
It's Gonna Be Bright.
I Know.
The Brain Cells
That Weren't Brain Cells
Were In The Way Of Processing
Visual Information Correctly.
After The Transplant,
You Could See,
But Not See.
I Could See.
I Could Read.
Yeah, But It Was Dull,
Or Foggy, Or Gray.
I Don't Know.
What I Do Know
Is That Yowere Not Seeing
What Everyone Else
Was Seeing.
And Now?
Things Are Gonna Be...
Beautiful?
Things'll Be
What They Are.
How Do I Look?
You Look Sad.
Hey.
Is There Any Way
I Could Put You On Retainer?